[
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "An apple of discord",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "cause of quarrel",
        "choices": [
            "cause of wealth",
            "cause of illness",
            "cause of happiness",
            "cause of quarrel"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Cut both hands",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "in favor of both sides",
        "choices": [
            "very big oss",
            "very hard worker",
            "in favor of both sides",
            "against both sides"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Roots and branch",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "",
        "choices": [
            "entirely",
            "step by step",
            "part by part",
            "bare truth"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A seminar is generally from of .......... interaction.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "formal",
        "choices": [
            "academic",
            "social",
            "formal",
            "artificial"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "An archaeologist studies about the .......... of human.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "past",
        "choices": [
            "rock",
            "history",
            "past",
            "future"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Back of beyond.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "a lonely forsaken place",
        "choices": [
            "an ideal place for holidays",
            "place with certain memories",
            "a religious place",
            "a lonely forsaken place"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Eat humble pie.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to apologize",
        "choices": [
            "to forgive",
            "to apologize",
            "to request",
            "to order"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of \"SUMMIT\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "peak",
        "choices": [
            "base",
            "slope",
            "declivity",
            "peak"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"FACULTY\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "branch",
        "choices": [
            "privilege",
            "desire",
            "branch",
            "ability"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"RECTIFY\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to correct",
        "choices": [
            "to command",
            "to correct",
            "to destroy",
            "to build"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give the antonym  of \"FICKLE\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "steadfast",
        "choices": [
            "steadfast",
            "independent",
            "unwise",
            "esoteric"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The antonym of \"CONFESS\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "deny",
        "choices": [
            "deny",
            "refuse",
            "contest",
            "contend"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What is the antonym of \"BASE\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "top",
        "choices": [
            "roof",
            "height",
            "top",
            "climax"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The meaning of \"palette\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "artist's paint mixing board",
        "choices": [
            "artist's brush keeping book",
            "artist's paint mixing board",
            "artist's drama box",
            "artist's planning board"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The word \"Saturated\" gives he meaning as:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "all",
        "choices": [
            "drenched",
            "soaked",
            "full of",
            "all"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Knowledge is like a deep well fed by .......... springs, and your mind is the little bucket that you drop in it.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "perennial",
        "choices": [
            "perennial",
            "eternal",
            "sterling",
            "immortal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "It was through to the second world war that Russia .......... herself increased .......... in power, wealth and prestige.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "witnessed, prodigiously",
        "choices": [
            "saw, abundantly",
            "notice, gullibly",
            "witnessed, prodigiously",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Those who seek .......... from others must learn to forgive and forget.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "leniency",
        "choices": [
            "leniency",
            "clemency",
            "courtesy",
            "retribution"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "His .......... of the topic was so good that students had few doubts to raise at the end.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "exposition",
        "choices": [
            "exposure",
            "clarity",
            "exposition",
            "picturization"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The accused was released on pending hearing of his case.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "bail",
        "choices": [
            "bale",
            "deposit",
            "bail",
            "bond"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He was killed .......... a highway man .......... a dagger.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "by; with",
        "choices": [
            "by; with",
            "with; for",
            "by; or",
            "in; for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Pakistan is not enamored .......... the bomb for its own sake.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "for",
            "with",
            "by"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He dispensed with the services .......... his honest clerk.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "by",
            "of",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The teacher has no control .......... the students.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "over",
        "choices": [
            "with",
            "at",
            "over",
            "on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "There is no hindrance .......... his going there.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "on",
            "over",
            "at"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I have a bistate .......... publicity",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "against",
        "choices": [
            "about",
            "at",
            "against",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "My cousin has invested a lot of money .......... farming",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "in",
        "choices": [
            "in",
            "for",
            "onto",
            "on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Plants absorb moisture .......... the air.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "from",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "in",
            "from",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "It is vain to calculate .......... an uncertain result.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "for",
        "choices": [
            "upon",
            "over",
            "into",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Jagdish had no servant to attend .......... him.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "upon",
            "over",
            "with",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The word 'quest' is meant for:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choices": [
            "to seek",
            "to look for",
            "to search",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Go to the dogs.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to be ruined",
        "choices": [
            "to be ruined",
            "to be in danger",
            "to take risk",
            "to disobey elders"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Keen is meant to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "very sensitive",
        "choices": [
            "very clean",
            "very warm",
            "very dull",
            "very sensitive"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Well disposed to",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "help to somebody",
        "choices": [
            "useless",
            "help to somebody",
            "very much excited",
            "to be settle for less"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Pay lip service.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "pretend to regard",
        "choices": [
            "false appreciation",
            "pretend to regard",
            "true relation",
            "false commitment"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Get on",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to step up",
        "choices": [
            "to step down",
            "to step up",
            "to help",
            "to think"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Above Board",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "honest and straightforward",
        "choices": [
            "boasting person",
            "honest and straightforward",
            "a man with arrogance",
            "a dishonest person"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Call a spade a spade",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to speak plainly",
        "choices": [
            "to disrespect",
            "to say in anger",
            "to speak plainly",
            "to manipulate"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Broadly speaking letters may be said to .......... Into two categories.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "fall",
        "choices": [
            "belong",
            "fall",
            "split",
            "convert"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The last decade has been .......... for management education and development.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "outstanding",
        "choices": [
            "dogmatic",
            "paradoxical",
            "praiseworthy",
            "outstanding"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Bandy words",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "To argue",
        "choices": [
            "to argue",
            "to request",
            "to give respect",
            "to be polite"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ever and Anon",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "sometimes",
        "choices": [
            "true promise",
            "false promise",
            "frequent",
            "sometimes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of \"Spurious\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "false",
        "choices": [
            "false",
            "harmful",
            "poisonous",
            "foreign"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"Annex\"",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "add",
        "choices": [
            "add",
            "low",
            "copy",
            "initial"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "GIve an exact synonym of \"Concert\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "agreement",
        "choices": [
            "beauty",
            "power",
            "agreement",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The antonym of \"Engage\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "abstain",
        "choices": [
            "abstain",
            "liberate",
            "release",
            "join"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What is the antonym of \"Moist\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "dry",
        "choices": [
            "parched",
            "dry",
            "hard",
            "crisp"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The meaning of \"shimmer\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choices": [
            "to flicker like sunlight",
            "to shine like sunlight",
            "to move like sunlight",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "THe word \"Snub\" gives meaning as:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choices": [
            "to ignore",
            "to avoid",
            "to shun",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The enemy paid a large sum as ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "compensation",
        "choices": [
            "redress",
            "amends",
            "compensation",
            "punishment"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... is a person who dabbles in arts and letters.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "dilettante",
        "choices": [
            "chauvinist",
            "connoisseur",
            "philistine",
            "dilettante"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We lost confidence on him because he never .......... the grandiose promises he made.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "delivered on",
        "choices": [
            "forgot",
            "tired",
            "delivered on",
            "relied upon"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "His .......... on his family's position is great but he does not boast about it.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "status",
        "choices": [
            "status",
            "pride",
            "deceit",
            "presumption"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Even when murunga's reputation was in .......... almost everyone was willing to admit that he had genius.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "eclipse",
        "choices": [
            "failure",
            "rebuttal",
            "accumulation",
            "eclipse"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Shyam was no control .......... his temper.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "over",
        "choices": [
            "after",
            "in",
            "over",
            "at"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She could not dissociate herself .......... what she said earlier.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "from",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "with",
            "off",
            "from"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We travelled .......... a boat to reach dhaka.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "by",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "on",
            "about",
            "by"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am used .......... such hardship.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "at",
            "from",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I was disappointed .......... not finding the doctor in his seat.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "from",
            "on",
            "at",
            "in"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ram is confident .......... his success.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "about",
            "towards",
            "of"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The reward was not commensurate .......... the work done by us.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "with",
        "choices": [
            "on",
            "for",
            "with",
            "order"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The citizens must not murmur .......... new taxes.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "against",
        "choices": [
            "over",
            "upon",
            "against",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What do you infer .......... this boy's hesitating behavior?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "with",
        "choices": [
            "from",
            "for",
            "with",
            "against"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "BEggar begged money .......... me.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "from",
            "by",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The word 'profuse' is meant for:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "an average number",
        "choices": [
            "not many",
            "an average number",
            "great abundance",
            "correct amount"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give a wide berth",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to motivate",
        "choices": [
            "to welcome",
            "to applaud",
            "to motivate",
            "to avoid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "When the church comes",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "moment of decision",
        "choices": [
            "moment of decision",
            "destination",
            "dotage",
            "win something"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "benevolent is meant to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "choices": [
            "generous",
            "kind",
            "good",
            "all of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Pyrrhic victory",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "victory at all cost",
        "choices": [
            "great victory",
            "victory with a policy",
            "much awaited victory",
            "victory at all cost"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Set people by ears.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to incite people",
        "choices": [
            "to incite people",
            "to listen carefully",
            "to give a long speech",
            "to abuse"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "To beg the question.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "to take for granted",
        "choices": [
            "to refer to",
            "to take for granted",
            "to raise objections",
            "to be discussed"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Cricket is a .......... game, but the destiny of the side is often shaped by a couple of individuals.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "team",
        "choices": [
            "good",
            "team",
            "popular",
            "new"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The .......... has to be precisely stated.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "theme",
        "choices": [
            "content",
            "criticism",
            "case",
            "theme"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Man worked with his small tools until the advent of modern machinery.......... by steam and electricity.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "driven",
        "choices": [
            "worked",
            "controlled",
            "driven",
            "moved"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The rest is history.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "known to everyone",
        "choices": [
            "history takes rest",
            "known to everyone",
            "to avoid historical facts",
            "history repeats"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Warm as toast.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "very fresh",
        "choices": [
            "cold",
            "very hot",
            "very fresh",
            "lukewarm"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The economy is finally ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "looking up",
        "choices": [
            "looking in",
            "looking on",
            "looking at",
            "looking up"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of \"Alien\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Stranger",
        "choices": [
            "Citizen",
            "Native",
            "Accustomed",
            "Stranger"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which one is appropriate synonym of \"Foster\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rear",
        "choices": [
            "Rear",
            "Encourage",
            "Nourish",
            "Promote"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give an exact synonym of \"Witty\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Ingenious",
        "choices": [
            "Ingenious",
            "Speedy",
            "Foolish",
            "Awkward"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The antonym of \"Abolish\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "establish",
        "choices": [
            "remove",
            "reside",
            "confront",
            "establish"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give the antonym of \"Salient\".",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "incline",
        "choices": [
            "emphatic",
            "striking",
            "important",
            "incline"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Demonstrating ood judgement is called:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "judicious",
        "choices": [
            "insinuate",
            "judicious",
            "masterpiece",
            "towering"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The study of society is called:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Sociology",
        "choices": [
            "Meteorology",
            "archeology",
            "Sociology",
            "geology"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Badminton is played on a court as wrestling in a",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "arena",
        "choices": [
            "court",
            "track",
            "ground",
            "arena"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "It was the help he got from his friends which .......... him through the tragedy.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "helped",
        "choices": [
            "boosted",
            "parked",
            "supported",
            "helped"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I never miss a cricket match. I .......... fond of cricket since childhood.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "have been",
        "choices": [
            "am",
            "will be",
            "have been",
            "has been"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What is the opposite of \"Mute\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "amplify",
        "choices": [
            "diversify",
            "quicken",
            "harmonize",
            "amplify"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The scientists made a .......... discovery for which he was honored.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "sensational",
        "choices": [
            "sensual",
            "sensational",
            "sensuous",
            "sentimental"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "That charming girl was the .......... of all eyes.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "ambition",
        "choices": [
            "aim",
            "target",
            "ambition",
            "cynosure"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He resembles .......... his mother.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "in",
            "with",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A son who is unable to look his father on the face is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "ashamed",
        "choices": [
            "guilty",
            "arrogant",
            "timid",
            "ashamed"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The thunder was accompanied .......... heavy rain.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "by",
        "choices": [
            "by",
            "with",
            "through",
            "up"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We passed.......... a lot of beautiful towns on the way to the resort.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "across",
        "choices": [
            "along",
            "across",
            "through",
            "all"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The child was hiding .......... the door.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "behind",
        "choices": [
            "behind",
            "below",
            "among",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "My parents got married .......... the 1970s.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "in",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "in",
            "from",
            "on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Many of us eat .......... fork and spoon.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "with",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "to",
            "on",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "How many people are .......... your team?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "on",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "on",
            "to",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She is very good .......... swimming",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "on",
            "of",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ravi will have arrived home .......... 8 pm tomorrow",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "by",
        "choices": [
            "in",
            "at",
            "by",
            "on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Rita is .......... honest and diligent student.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "an",
        "choices": [
            "a",
            "an",
            "this",
            "no article"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The passive version of \"Who did it?\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Who was it done by?",
        "choices": [
            "Who was it done?",
            "Who was it done by?",
            "Who was done it?",
            "Who had it done by?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We had to stop .......... the entrance for the security check.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "in",
            "on",
            "at",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Using a .......... cleaner is the best way for avoiding the dust pollution.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "vacuum",
        "choices": [
            "vaccum",
            "vacume",
            "vacuum",
            "vacuume"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The plural form of \"ox\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "oxen",
        "choices": [
            "oxen",
            "oxes",
            "oxez",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The feminine form of deer is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "doe",
        "choices": [
            "deeress",
            "doe",
            "stag",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "If I had know about your arrival, I .......... to receive you at the airport.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "would have come",
        "choices": [
            "would come",
            "would came",
            "would have come",
            "had come"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "At midnight, all the goats were ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "bleating",
        "choices": [
            "bleating",
            "howling",
            "roaring",
            "mowing"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The question tag of \"They have already arrived,\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "haven't they?",
        "choices": [
            "have they?",
            "haven't they?",
            "weren't they?",
            "did they?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Please .......... the cigarette. It irritates me.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "put out",
        "choices": [
            "put down",
            "put out",
            "put away",
            "put in"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "As Gretel's father could not do anything, he gave ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "away",
        "choices": [
            "away",
            "out",
            "in",
            "into"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I have eaten nothing for hours. I am .......... hungry.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "quite",
        "choices": [
            "quiet",
            "quit",
            "quite",
            "queit"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of recurring is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "occurring repeatedly",
        "choices": [
            "occurring repeatedly",
            "happening rarely",
            "occurring once a week",
            "occurring seldom"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The antonym of \"on\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "off",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "un",
            "off",
            "out"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... he was very popular among common people, he could not win the election.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Although",
        "choices": [
            "Because",
            "So",
            "Although",
            "Therefore"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The indirect speech of \"Are you sure ? She said to me\", is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "She asked me if I was sure.",
        "choices": [
            "She asked me if I was sure.",
            "She wanted to know was I sure.",
            "She inquired if I am sure.",
            "She asked him if I was sure."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "In the night bus yesterday, I had my purse ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "stolen",
        "choices": [
            "steal",
            "stole",
            "stolen",
            "to steal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am looking forward to .......... you very soon again.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "seeing",
        "choices": [
            "see",
            "seen",
            "seeing",
            "be seen"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I bought this pen from the .......... store.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "stationery",
        "choices": [
            "stationery",
            "stationary",
            "stationnary",
            "stantianory"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "This bed is not .......... for two people to sleep in.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "wide enough",
        "choices": [
            "as wide as",
            "wide enough",
            "wider enough",
            "quite weaker"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The fault in the engine is .......... this time than it was the last time.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "more serious",
        "choices": [
            "more serious",
            "seriouser",
            "very serious",
            "serious than"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "You will find the photograph of mine .......... page 13.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "on",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "on",
            "of",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Reeta can dance .......... of all in this class.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "the best",
        "choices": [
            "the best",
            "better",
            "best",
            "more better"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Hurry up and use the .........., the house is on fire.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "extinguisher",
        "choices": [
            "extincter",
            "extinguisher",
            "extinguishing",
            "extinguish"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The tag question of \"I am an engineer,\" is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "aren't I?",
        "choices": [
            "aren't I?",
            "am not I?",
            "don't I?",
            "ain't I?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am in a state of dilemma. That means I am ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "puzzled",
        "choices": [
            "dazzled",
            "tired",
            "puzzled",
            "not sure"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She undergoes a strange experience of seeing something not present in front of her. In other words, she is suffering from ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "hallucination",
        "choices": [
            "hallucination",
            "bronchitis",
            "tonsillitis",
            "psychosis"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She can play tennis, but she is .......... at it than her friend.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "worse",
        "choices": [
            "badly",
            "worse",
            "more badly",
            "worsley"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Sulav sold his plot of land in the village so that he .......... buy a new house in the city.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "could",
        "choices": [
            "could",
            "can",
            "need",
            "would"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "If you teased the dog, it .......... bite you.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "might",
        "choices": [
            "would",
            "may",
            "can",
            "might"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of purgatory is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "heaven",
        "choices": [
            "polluted city",
            "hell",
            "heaven",
            "sky"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The synonym of creek is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "rivulet",
        "choices": [
            "pond",
            "late",
            "rivulet",
            "tributary"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "No sooner had I left the room, the bomb .......... exploded.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "had",
        "choices": [
            "had",
            "could be",
            "would be",
            "none of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Sarita play chess .......... than her sister",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "better",
        "choices": [
            "more better",
            "better",
            "well",
            "best"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am looking forward to .......... you soon.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "seeing",
        "choices": [
            "seeing",
            "see",
            "be seen",
            "seen"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Because of the heavy rain, they decided to call .......... the cricket match.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "off",
        "choices": [
            "out",
            "up",
            "off",
            "down"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Cholera broke .......... in Jajarkot ten years ago.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "out",
        "choices": [
            "out",
            "down",
            "up",
            "into"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The danger of volcanoes .......... not be taken lightly.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "must",
        "choices": [
            "must",
            "might",
            "has",
            "have"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ramesh .......... here for the last seven years.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "has worked",
        "choices": [
            "worked",
            "is working",
            "has worked",
            "works"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Let us go, ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "shall we?",
        "choices": [
            "shall we?",
            "will we?",
            "do we?",
            "don't we?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Two ladies had .......... hand bags stolen at the Kathmandu Mal.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "their",
        "choices": [
            "its",
            "her",
            "their",
            "they"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "They are as lucky as ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "we",
        "choices": [
            "we",
            "our",
            "ourselves",
            "us"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Sincere people abide .......... their promise.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "by",
        "choices": [
            "by",
            "of",
            "at",
            "on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The new manager will .......... his position on August 30.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "take over",
        "choices": [
            "take of",
            "take out",
            "take over",
            "take after"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He got a Lion's share of profits.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "greater share of things",
        "choices": [
            "no share at all",
            "greater share of things",
            "very small part",
            "little profit"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Neither of them .......... a problem.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "anticipates",
        "choices": [
            "anticipate",
            "anticipates",
            "have anticipated",
            "are anticipating"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "There is someone in the room .......... I certainly heard a great noise.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "for",
        "choices": [
            "and",
            "but",
            "for",
            "so"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She is .......... obedient student.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "an",
        "choices": [
            "an",
            "a",
            "the",
            "none of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I don't think I .......... be able to go.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "will",
        "choices": [
            "will",
            "should",
            "can",
            "could"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "That which cannot be divided.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "indivisible",
        "choices": [
            "indelible",
            "indivisible",
            "insoluble",
            "indefensible"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is an abstract noun?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "fear",
        "choices": [
            "desk",
            "fear",
            "calss",
            "needle"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following  words does not have a suffix?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "courage",
        "choices": [
            "helpless",
            "goodness",
            "fearless",
            "courage"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The opposite meaning of 'accepted' is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "rejected",
        "choices": [
            "liked",
            "noted",
            "provided",
            "rejected"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the word nearest in meaning to 'emulate'.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Imitate",
        "choices": [
            "Imitate",
            "Deny",
            "Discuss",
            "Reject"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Raman is a versatile boy.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "gifted",
        "choices": [
            "bad",
            "clumsy",
            "gifted",
            "lazy"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Select the correct antonym for 'segregation'.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "cohesion",
        "choices": [
            "appreciation",
            "integration",
            "cohesion",
            "co-ordination"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The price of consumer goods .......... increasing.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "is",
        "choices": [
            "are",
            "is",
            "were",
            "has been"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following sentences is incorrect in terms of subject verb agreement?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Here is a hammer and two wrenches.",
        "choices": [
            "Each of the women owns her home.",
            "All of the women own their own homes.",
            "Here are two wrenches and a hammer.",
            "Here is a hammer and two wrenches."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following sentences has the correct use of comma (,)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "We were glad to see him, because he had brought gifts.",
        "choices": [
            "June 27, 2018, is a day I will never forget.",
            "Some people who go to school, enjoy the social life.",
            "He was late for dinner, we decided to eat without him.",
            "We were glad to see him, because he had brought gifts."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the part participate of the verb quit.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "quit",
        "choices": [
            "quitted",
            "quit",
            "quitting",
            "has quit"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We spent a .......... evening together.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "quite",
        "choices": [
            "quite",
            "quit",
            "quitting",
            "quitter"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following words needs capitalization?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "jewish",
        "choices": [
            "winter",
            "ocean",
            "jewish",
            "university"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He is occurred .......... cheating.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "for",
            "of",
            "on",
            "in"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He is coming here .......... six o'clock",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "upon",
            "in",
            "at",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "In the good book of",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "enjoying a favour of someone.",
        "choices": [
            "enjoying a pleasant moment.",
            "enjoying a favour of someone.",
            "possessing a good book for reading.",
            "purchasing a good book."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am .......... tired to go any further",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "too",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "too",
            "so",
            "not"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Hari says, \"I am very happy\"",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Hari says he is very happy.",
        "choices": [
            "Hari says he is very happy.",
            "Hari says he was very happy.",
            "Hari said he is very happy.",
            "Hari said he was very happy."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Select the interrogative sentence from the given options below",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Shall I see you tomorrow?",
        "choices": [
            "Shall I see you tomorrow?",
            "He has studied English for a long time.",
            "They won't believe you.",
            "It will be dark soon."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I .......... told you earlier if I had known.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "would have",
        "choices": [
            "would",
            "would have",
            "had",
            "should"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "If everybody does .......... part, the game should go smoothly.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "his or her",
        "choices": [
            "his",
            "her",
            "his or her",
            "their"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following word is an adverb?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "well",
        "choices": [
            "good",
            "bad",
            "well",
            "melt"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Man worked with his small tools until the advent of mordern machinery .......... by steam and electricity.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "driven",
        "choices": [
            "worked",
            "controlled",
            "driven",
            "moved"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The famous Bulbul lake is situated in:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Surkhet",
        "choices": [
            "Gorkha",
            "Chitwan",
            "Tanahun",
            "Surkhet"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The oldest country in the world is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "San marino",
        "choices": [
            "Vatican City",
            "Libya",
            "San marino",
            "Denmark"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The first daily newspaper of the world is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "The Morning Post",
        "choices": [
            "The Morning Post",
            "Sunday Times",
            "The New York Times",
            "Daily Mail"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "In computer abbreviation of CAD usually means?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Computer Aided Design",
        "choices": [
            "Computer Additional Design",
            "Computer Aided Data",
            "Computer Aided Design",
            "Computer Assist Design"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the current secretary general of the UN?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Antonio Guterres",
        "choices": [
            "Wan ki Moon",
            "U thant",
            "Antonio Guterres",
            "Kofi Annan"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The national game of Nepl is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Volleyball",
        "choices": [
            "Cricket",
            "Volleyball",
            "Kabaddi",
            "Football"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The CEO of Google is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Sundar Pichai",
        "choices": [
            "Satya Nadella",
            "Jeff Bezos",
            "Warren Buffet",
            "Sundar Pichai"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the capital of Canada?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Ottawa",
        "choices": [
            "Ottawa",
            "Canberra",
            "Vancouver",
            "Winnipeg"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Logarithm tables were invented by:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "John Napier",
        "choices": [
            "Blaise Pascal",
            "John Napier",
            "Charles Babbage",
            "John Douglas"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is known as the father of Internet?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Tim Berners-Lee",
        "choices": [
            "Lawrence Roberts",
            "Ray Tomlinson",
            "Vint Cerf",
            "Tim Berners-Lee"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The famous Halesi Mahadev temple is situated in:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Morang",
        "choices": [
            "Taplejung",
            "Khotang",
            "Sarlahi",
            "Morang"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The oldest flag in the world is of:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Denmark",
        "choices": [
            "Italy",
            "Russia",
            "Denmark",
            "China"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The Guitar was fristly introduced from:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Spain",
        "choices": [
            "Spain",
            "Germany",
            "France",
            "America"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "In computer abbreviation of AI usually means?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Artificial Internet",
        "choices": [
            "Art info",
            "Artificial Intelligence",
            "Artificial interest",
            "Artificial Internet"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the current vice chancellor fo the Tribhuvan University?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Tritha Khaniya",
        "choices": [
            "Dilli Pd. Sapkota",
            "Shivalal BHusal",
            "Ram Pd. Khatiwada",
            "Tritha Khaniya"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The national game of Bhutan is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Archery",
        "choices": [
            "cricket",
            "Archery",
            "Bull fighting",
            "Football"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The CEO of Apple is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Tim Cook",
        "choices": [
            "Satya Nadela",
            "Tim Cook",
            "Sao Paulo",
            "Salvador"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Brasilia",
        "choices": [
            "Brasilia",
            "Rio de Janeiro",
            "So Paulo",
            "Salvador"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the capatain of Nepal's National Football team?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Kiran Chemjong",
        "choices": [
            "Anil Gurung",
            "Bimal Gharti Magar",
            "Kiran Chemjong",
            "Biraj Maharjan"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which country is known as 'the gift of Nile'?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Egypt",
        "choices": [
            "Iraq",
            "Iran",
            "Egypt",
            "Italy"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Nepal was hit by the 7.8 magnitude Earthquake on:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2072 Baisakh 12",
        "choices": [
            "2072 Baisakh 10",
            "2072 Baisakh 11",
            "2072 Baisakh 12",
            "2072 Baisakh 13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The new constitution of Nepal, \"Nepal Ko Sambidhan\" was released on:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2072 Asoj 3",
        "choices": [
            "2072 Asoj 4",
            "2072 Asoj 3",
            "2072 Asoj 2",
            "2072 Asoj 1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the writer of Novel Ek Chihan ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Hridaychandra Singh Pradhan",
        "choices": [
            "Hridaychandra Singh Pradhan",
            "Krishnachandra Singh Pradhan",
            "Bijay Bahadur Malla",
            "Parijat"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Kusti is played on:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Akhada",
        "choices": [
            "Ground",
            "Court",
            "Ring",
            "Akhada"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is considered as the father of computer?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Charles Babbage",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Babbage",
            "Bill Gates",
            "Mark Zukerberg",
            "Chiris Huhes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which one of the following is the database program ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "MySQL",
        "choices": [
            "MySQL",
            "MS-Excel",
            "MS-Word",
            "MS-Outlook"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the full form of LCD ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Liquid Crystal Display",
        "choices": [
            "Light and Clear Display",
            "Liquid Cristal Display",
            "Liquid Crystal Display",
            "Liquid Clear Display"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which is the first bank in Nepal?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Nepal Bank Limited",
        "choices": [
            "Nepal Bank Limited",
            "Rastriya Banijya Bank",
            "Nepal Investment Bank",
            "Nepal Rastra Bank"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which of the following field is not awarded by Nobel Prize?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Computer Science",
        "choices": [
            "Computer Science",
            "Physics",
            "Economics",
            "Literature"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "How many provinces (Pradesh) are in Nepal according to the new consitution ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "7",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "When did the new constitute of Nepal \"Nepal Ko Sambidhan\" was released?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2072 Ashoj 3",
        "choices": [
            "2072 Ashoj 4",
            "2072 Ashoj 3",
            "2072 Ashoj 2 d",
            "2072 Ashoj 1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is known as \"Father of Computer\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Charles Babbage",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Babbage",
            "Bill Gates",
            "Mark Zuckerberg",
            "John V Neumann"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which one of the following discipline is not awarded by noble prize?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Computer Science",
        "choices": [
            "Literature",
            "Economics",
            "Physics",
            "Computer Science"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which one of the following belongs to SSD?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Mass Storage",
        "choices": [
            "Cache Memory",
            "ROM",
            "RAM",
            "Mass Storage"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who won the FIFA World Cup 2018 held in Russia?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "France",
        "choices": [
            "England",
            "Coratia",
            "France",
            "Germany"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which one of the following is not an output device?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "OCR",
        "choices": [
            "OCR",
            "Plotter",
            "Monitor",
            "Printer"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "What is the scientific name of human?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Homosepian",
        "choices": [
            "Rana Tigrina",
            "Homosepian",
            "Felis Catus",
            "Rattus"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which one of the following is the deepest river of the Nepal?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Karnali",
        "choices": [
            "Karnali",
            "KOshi",
            "Mahakali",
            "Gandaki"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who was the first prime minister of Nepal?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Bhimsen Thapa",
        "choices": [
            "Janga Bahadur Rana",
            "Matrika Prasad Koirala",
            "Bhimsen Thapa",
            "Mathabar Sing Thapa"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the writer of the Nepal novel \"Basain\"?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Lil Bahadur Kshetri",
        "choices": [
            "Lil Bahadur Kshetri",
            "Ramlal Joshi",
            "Gopal Prasad Rimal",
            "Lokendra Bahadur Chand"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The famous Manakamana Temple is situated in:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Gorkha",
        "choices": [
            "Gorkha",
            "Chitwan",
            "Tanahun",
            "Dhanding"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The Effiel tower is situated is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Paris",
        "choices": [
            "London",
            "Tokyo",
            "Paris",
            "Madrid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a programming langage?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Arduino",
        "choices": [
            "C#",
            "JAVA",
            "Python",
            "Arduino"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The largest network category based on coverage area is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "WAN",
        "choices": [
            "LAN",
            "WAN",
            "MAN",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "How many permanent members are there in security council of UN?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "10",
            "4",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Rafael Nadal is associated with:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Long Tennis",
        "choices": [
            "Cricket",
            "Long Tennis",
            "HOckey",
            "Wrestling"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The first President of Nepal is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Dr. Ram Baran Yadav",
        "choices": [
            "Bidhya Devi Bhandari",
            "Puspha Kamal Dahal",
            "Sher Bahadur Deuba",
            "Dr. Ram Baran Yadav"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "The letter's in HTTPs understands for:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Secured",
        "choices": [
            "Scared",
            "Secured",
            "Shape",
            "Shine"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Who is the captain of Nepal's National Cricket team?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Parash Khadka",
        "choices": [
            "Anil Gurung",
            "Gyanendra Malla",
            "Rohit Poudel",
            "Parash Khadka"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge",
        "question": "Which city is known as 'City of Temple'?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Kathmandu",
        "choices": [
            "Phuket",
            "New York",
            "Kathmandu",
            "Rome"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one of the following number has a remainder of 4 when it is divided by 6?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "22",
        "choices": [
            "8",
            "12",
            "22",
            "29"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of the product and quotient of 4 and 4 is ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "17",
        "choices": [
            "16",
            "15",
            "8",
            "17"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The average of all even numbers between -4 and 5 is ..........",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "0.5",
            "-1",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of first five prime numbers is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "28",
        "choices": [
            "11",
            "18",
            "26",
            "28"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\sum_{n=0}^{10} \\left( -1 \\right)^{n}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "-1",
            "10",
            "0"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The product of two consecutive even number is 224. Then the number are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "14,16",
        "choices": [
            "16,18",
            "12,14",
            "14,16",
            "18,20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 5 is added to the square of a number, then the result is 14. What is the value of that number?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "5",
            "7",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If three spoons equals to one glass, two glasses equals to one place, then how many spoons equals to one plate?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "6",
            "9",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a matrix is of order 5 x 7, then each column will contain .......... elements.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "12",
            "35",
            "7"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the equations are \\(3x + 4y = 7\\) and \\(4x - y = 3\\), after solving these equations the value of x and y will be:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1,1",
        "choices": [
            "1,1",
            "1,2",
            "2,1",
            "2,2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\(x\\) in series 1, 9, 25, \\(x\\), 81, 121?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "49",
        "choices": [
            "100",
            "36",
            "49",
            "64"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a + b = c\\), then what is the average value of \\(x\\), \\(b\\) and \\(c\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{2c}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{a+b}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{a+b+c}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2c}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{c}{3}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x\\) is an integer and \\(y = -2x - 8\\), what is the least value of \\(x\\) for which \\(y\\) is less than 9?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "-8",
        "choices": [
            "-8",
            "-9",
            "-10",
            "-11"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of line which equation is \\(2x - 4y = 9\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the slope of horizontal line?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            ">1",
            "<0",
            "0",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The difference between 3/5 of 80 and 30% of 80 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "24",
        "choices": [
            "20",
            "14",
            "15",
            "24"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Gautam spent Rs. 40/-, which is 5% of his daily wage, then his total daily wage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 800/-",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 400/-",
            "Rs. 600/-",
            "Rs. 800/-",
            "Rs. 1000/-"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 1254376 represents the CENTURY, then what represents 735?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "RUN",
        "choices": [
            "NUT",
            "RUT",
            "RUN",
            "YET"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Find the missing value in \\(\\begin{bmatrix}2&  7& 6\\\\9&  5&  1\\\\4&  3& ?\\end{bmatrix}\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "8",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "8",
            "7",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "There are 48 students in a computer class. If number of boys are twice than girls, then how many girls are there ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "16",
        "choices": [
            "16",
            "18",
            "32",
            "28"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Find the number \\(x\\), which is equal to (80% of \\(x\\)) plus 5.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25",
        "choices": [
            "20",
            "30",
            "40",
            "25"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the ratio of two numbers is \\(2:3\\) and sum of these numbers is 30, then which are these numbers?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12,18",
        "choices": [
            "14,16",
            "10,20",
            "12,18",
            "18,12"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the age of five girls are 15, 16, 17, 18, 19 respectively then what is the average age of girls?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "17",
        "choices": [
            "15",
            "17",
            "18",
            "19"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\(cos60^{\\circ}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "0",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Find the value of \\(x\\) in series 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, \\(x\\).",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "21",
        "choices": [
            "21",
            "22",
            "19",
            "23"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "if '\\(n\\)' is an integer, which of the following must be even?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2n\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(n + 1\\)",
            "\\(n + 2\\)",
            "\\(2n + 1\\)",
            "\\(2n\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The largest prime factor of 255 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "17",
        "choices": [
            "45",
            "25",
            "17",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of first \\(n\\) natural number is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{n(n+1}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{n(n+1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{(n+1)^{2}}{2}\\)",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The root of the equation \\(3x^{2} - 8x + 16 = 0\\) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "imaginary & unequal",
        "choices": [
            "real & equal",
            "real & unequal",
            "imaginary & unequal",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x + y = 12\\) and \\(x - y = 6\\) then, the value of \\(x^{2} - y^{2}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "72",
        "choices": [
            "18",
            "36",
            "60",
            "72"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x - 5 = 2\\), then value of \\(x + 12\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "19",
        "choices": [
            "15",
            "17",
            "19",
            "18"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value when simplified \\(\\frac{6^{4} - 6^{3}}{5}\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(6^{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)",
            "\\(6^{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{6}{5}\\)",
            "\\(6^{4}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(\\frac{4}{a} + \\frac{4}{a} + \\frac{4}{a} + \\frac{4}{a} = 16\\) then, \\(4a\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "8",
            "12",
            "16"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of line \\(\\frac{x}{a} + \\frac{y}{b} = 1\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(-\\frac{b}{a}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(-\\frac{a}{b}\\)",
            "\\(-\\frac{b}{a}\\)",
            "\\(ab\\)",
            "\\(-\\frac{1}{ab}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x = 4y\\), what percent of \\(2x \\space is \\space 2y\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "40%",
            "30%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the cost of 9 kg sugar is Rs. 270/-, how much sugar can be purchased for Rs. 390/-?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "13",
        "choices": [
            "11",
            "12",
            "13",
            "14"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 3 bananas cost 50 cents, how many bananas can be bought for 20 dollars?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "120",
        "choices": [
            "120",
            "115",
            "110",
            "130"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(5:7 = 15:x\\), then the value of \\(x\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "21",
        "choices": [
            "35",
            "21",
            "27",
            "18"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "By selling 150 apples, the seller gains the selling price of 30 apples, then gain percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "25%",
            "30%",
            "12%",
            "20%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A vendor purchases lemons at Rs. 5/- per lemon, at what price vendor will sell lemon to gain 20% profit ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 6/-",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 4/-",
            "Rs. 5/-",
            "Rs. 6/-",
            "Rs. 7/-"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the population doubling time if population growth rate is 2% per annum ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "50yrs",
            "30yrs",
            "40yrs",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The cardinal number of a vowel set \\(V = \\left\\{a, e, i, o, u \\right\\}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "5",
            "6",
            "7"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(log_{a}81 = 4\\), then the value of '\\(a\\)' is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "3",
            "5",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{18}}{\\sqrt{72}}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "a rational number",
        "choices": [
            "a rational number",
            "an irrational number",
            "an imaginary number",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(\\frac{5}{7}\\) of a number is 1025, then \\(\\frac{3}{7}\\) of number is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "615",
        "choices": [
            "735",
            "430",
            "615",
            "560"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The number of seconds in \\(1\\frac{1}{2}\\) hours is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5400",
        "choices": [
            "5100",
            "5200",
            "5300",
            "5400"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The \\(4m\\) wide carpet is used for carpeting a room of \\(8m\\) long and \\(3m\\) wide, then what is the length of carpet?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(6m\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(5m\\)",
            "\\(6m\\)",
            "\\(2m\\)",
            "\\(3m\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Hari ranks seventh from the top and twenty sixth from the bottom in a class. Then the total number of students in a class are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "32",
        "choices": [
            "35",
            "35",
            "31",
            "32"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The three girls write 3 pages in 3 minutes, in how many minutes can one girl write one page?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3 min",
        "choices": [
            "4 min",
            "5 min",
            "3 min",
            "6 min"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of a vertical line is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "not defined",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "more than 0",
            "not defined",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(P(A\\cap B)) = 0\\), two events are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "mutually exclusive",
        "choices": [
            "mutually exclusive",
            "equally like events",
            "exhaustive events",
            "dependent events"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which of the following is the true statement ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(0 \\in\\left\\{0  \\right\\}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(0 \\in\\left\\{  \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(0 \\in\\left\\{0  \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(0 \\in\\left\\{1  \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(0 \\subset\\left\\{ 0 \\right\\}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Each prime number has:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "only two factors",
        "choices": [
            "no factor",
            "only one factor",
            "only two factors",
            "more than two factors"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the function \\(f(x) = 2^{2} - 5x + 2\\), then the value of \\(\\frac{f(4 + h) - f(4)}{h}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "\\(11 - 2h\\)",
            "\\(11 + 2h\\)",
            "\\(2h - 11\\)",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the sum of three terms of an A.P is 51 and product of last and first term is 273, the numbers are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "21,17,13",
        "choices": [
            "21,15,13",
            "21,17,13",
            "19,17,13",
            "19,15,13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\cosec60^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = (a_{ij})_{m\\times n}\\) and \\(B = (a_{ij})_{m\\times n}\\) be any two matrices and \\(A + B\\) defined, the order of \\(A + B\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(m\\times n\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(m\\times n\\)",
            "\\(n\\times m\\)",
            "\\(m\\times m\\)",
            "\\(n\\times n\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of the four wall, ceiling and floor of a room is \\(56m^{2}\\). If the room is \\(3m\\) long and \\(2m\\) wide, the height of room is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(4.4m\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(4.9m\\)",
            "\\(5m\\)",
            "\\(4.7m\\)",
            "\\(4.4m\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "One half of a number is 17 more than one-third of that number. What is the number ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "102",
        "choices": [
            "52",
            "84",
            "102",
            "112"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Two numbers are respectively 20% and 50% more than the third number. What % is the first number of the second ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "80%",
        "choices": [
            "40%",
            "50%",
            "80%",
            "70%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Hari spent Rs. 25 which is 15% of his monthly wage. His monthly wage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. \\(166\\frac{2}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 80",
            "Rs. \\(166\\frac{2}{3}\\)",
            "Rs. 225",
            "Rs. 312.5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one is perpendicular to line \\(2x + 3y = 4\\) ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(3x + 2y = 8\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2x - 3y = 5\\)",
            "\\(2x - 3y + 7 = 0\\)",
            "\\(3x + 2y = 8\\)",
            "\\(3x - 2y + 7 = 0\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The interest on a sum of money of 6% for 2.5 years is Rs. 270, the amount is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2070",
        "choices": [
            "4000",
            "2070",
            "4100",
            "4150"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A man gains the selling price of 5 books by selling 25 books. The percentage gain is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "25.5%",
            "15%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "I lost 7% by selling an article for Rs. 139.50. At what price must I have sold it to have 10% gain ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "165",
        "choices": [
            "150",
            "165",
            "175",
            "200"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Two sides of a right-angled triangle are 12cm and 13cm. The length of third side of right-angled triangle is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5 units",
        "choices": [
            "5 units",
            "11 units",
            "12 units",
            "56 units"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The volume of a wall which is built by using 3000 bricks having the dimension \\(14cm\\times 10cm\\times 6cm\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2.52m^{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2.52m^{3}\\)",
            "\\(2.25m^{3}\\)",
            "\\(3.25m^{3}\\)",
            "\\(3.52m^{3}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A vendor lemon at 6 for a rupee, how many for a rupee must be sold to gain 20% ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "6",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\sec55^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The interest on a sum of money is 3/11 of the amounts in 3 years. The rate of interest is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "choices": [
            "13.5%",
            "13%",
            "12.5%",
            "12%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Jack is now 14 years older than Bill. If in 10 years Jack will be twice as old as Bill, how old will Jack be in 5 years ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "23",
        "choices": [
            "21",
            "23",
            "25",
            "27"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 2 is subtracted from the square of a number and the result is 7, the number is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\pm3\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\pm3\\)",
            "\\(\\pm4\\)",
            "\\(\\pm5\\)",
            "\\(\\pm6\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the area of the square region having sides of length 6cm is equal to the area of rectangular region having width 2.5cm, then the length of the rectangle (in cm) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "14.4",
        "choices": [
            "8.5",
            "12",
            "13",
            "14.4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The solution of the set of equations \\(x - y = 2\\) & \\(2x + 3y = 9\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3,1",
        "choices": [
            "1,3",
            "2,1",
            "3,2",
            "3,1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The interval satisfying \\(3 \\le x-1 \\le 5 \\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\left[ 4,6 \\right]",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left[ 3,5 \\right] \\)",
            "\\(\\left[ 4,6 \\right] \\)",
            "\\(\\left[ 2,3 \\right] \\)",
            "\\(\\left[ 2,3 \\right ]\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The constant function is a:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "onto",
        "choices": [
            "one to one",
            "onto",
            "into",
            "objective"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\((2 + \\sqrt{3})(2 - \\sqrt{3})(3 + \\sqrt{5})(3 - \\sqrt{5})\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "rational number",
        "choices": [
            "rational number",
            "irrational number",
            "an imaginary number",
            "all of above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x + y = \\frac{4c}{5},\\space y + z = \\frac{7c}{5} \\space and \\space z + x = \\frac{9c}{5}\\), \\(\\space\\) the \\(\\space\\) value \\(\\space\\) of \\(\\space\\) \\(x + y + z\\):",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2c\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{7c}{15}\\)",
            "\\(c\\)",
            "\\(2c\\)",
            "\\(3c\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Divide of Rs. 750 into three parts in the ration \\(4:5:6\\) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "200, 250, 300",
        "choices": [
            "200, 250, 300",
            "250, 250, 250",
            "350, 250, 150",
            "400, 500, 600"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The ratio \\(5:4\\) expressed as percent equals to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "120%",
        "choices": [
            "115%",
            "125%",
            "120%",
            "130%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(1+\\frac{1}{x}\\space=\\space2-\\frac{2}{x}\\), the value of \\(x\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of rectangular courtyard is \\(63m^{2}\\) and perimeter is \\(32m\\). The length and breadth (in m) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "9,7",
        "choices": [
            "4,3",
            "9,7",
            "29,17",
            "19,13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(\\frac{1}{x + 4}+\\frac{1}{x+1}=\\frac{1}{x}\\), then \\(x\\) could be",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(-2\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\pm1\\)",
            "\\(\\pm2\\)",
            "\\(-2\\)",
            "\\(-4\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Three sides of the triangle are in the ration \\(1:2:3\\), it is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "a right-angled triangle",
            "an isosceles triangle",
            "an equilateral triangle",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x\\) is an integer and \\(y = 2x - 8\\), what is the least value of \\(x\\) for which \\(y\\) is less than 9 ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "-8",
        "choices": [
            "-9",
            "-8",
            "-7",
            "-6"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of the series 24,3,8,1,2,7 upto \\(8^{th}\\) term is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(57\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(57\\)",
            "\\(36\\frac{13}{50}\\)",
            "\\(36\\frac{1}{9}\\)",
            "\\(37\\frac{5}{9}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(t_{n}\\space=\\space2n^{2}\\space+\\space3n\\), the value of \\(S_{4}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "90",
        "choices": [
            "90",
            "85",
            "80",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the \\(n^{th}\\) term of the series 3,10,17 .......... and 63,65,67 .......... are equal, the value of n is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "13",
        "choices": [
            "8",
            "10",
            "12",
            "13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the cost price of 18 pens and selling price of 20 pens are equal. The loss percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "11.11%",
        "choices": [
            "10.5%",
            "10%",
            "11.11%",
            "13%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A person incurs a loss of 10% by selling a toy for Rs. 10.80. At what price should he sell it to earn a profit of 20% ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "14.4",
        "choices": [
            "12",
            "12.96",
            "14.4",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A machine was bought for Rs. 7540 and sold at a profit of 20%, the selling price was",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "9048",
        "choices": [
            "9048",
            "9049",
            "9050",
            "9051"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A 30% discount reduces the price of a commodity by Rs. 90. If the discount is reduced to 20% then the price of the commodity will be:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 240",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 180",
            "Rs. 210",
            "Rs. 240",
            "Rs. 300"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = \\begin{bmatrix}2&3 \\\\-5&-2\\end{bmatrix}\\), the value of \\(A^{-1}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{11}A\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(A\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{3}A\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{19}A\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{11}A\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\begin{bmatrix}a-6&2a \\\\-2b&a-6\\end{bmatrix}\\) equals to",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((a + 6)^{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(a + 6\\)",
            "\\(a - 6\\)",
            "\\((a + 6)^{2}\\)",
            "\\(b + a + 1\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The simple interest on Rs. 400 for 1 year at 5% p.a. is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20",
        "choices": [
            "20",
            "25",
            "16",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of money at the rate of 5% p.a will yield an interest of Rs. 120 in 3 years is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "800",
        "choices": [
            "800",
            "900",
            "1000",
            "1100"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a:b\\space=\\space 2:3,\\space b:c\\space=\\space 5:7\\), the value of \\(a:b:c\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2:3:7\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2:3:7\\)",
            "\\(2:5:7\\)",
            "\\(10:15:21\\)",
            "\\(2:15:7\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of the line passing through \\((a, b)\\) and \\((\\frac{1}{a}, b)\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "4",
            "3",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(P(A\\cup B)\\space=\\space1\\), two events \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) are",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "exhaustive events",
        "choices": [
            "mutually exclusive",
            "equally likely events",
            "exhaustive events",
            "dependent events"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The set \\(\\left\\{ x:x^{2}+x+1\\space=\\space0, x\\in R \\right\\}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\left\\{ \\right\\}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left\\{1, \\sqrt{3} \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\left\\{-1, \\sqrt{3} \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\left\\{ \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\((-1,0)\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Every rational number is also",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "a real number",
        "choices": [
            "natural number",
            "a whole number",
            "an integer number",
            "a real number"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(f(u)\\space=\\space\\frac{u}{u-1}\\), then \\(\\frac{f(a)}{f(a+1)}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(f(a^{2})\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(f(-a)\\)",
            "\\(f(\\frac{1}{a})\\)",
            "\\(f(a^{2})\\)",
            "\\(f(\\frac{-a}{a+1})\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the term of an AP is 2 and the common difference is 4. The sum of its 40 terms is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3200",
        "choices": [
            "3200",
            "1600",
            "300",
            "1750"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\cot30^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(AB\\space=\\space C\\) exists, which of the following order of matrices is possible ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(A_{32},\\space B_{23},\\space C_{32}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(A_{23},\\space B_{32},\\space C_{23}\\)",
            "\\(A_{32},\\space B_{23},\\space C_{32}\\)",
            "\\(A_{32},\\space B_{23},\\space C_{33}\\)",
            "\\(A_{33},\\space B_{23},\\space C_{33}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of 4 walls of square room is \\(120m^{2}\\). If the height is \\(5m\\), the area of its floor is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(36m^{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(56m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(36m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(46m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(26m^{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "One-third of a number is 20 more than one-fifth of that number. What is the number ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "150",
        "choices": [
            "30",
            "84",
            "102",
            "150"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\begin{vmatrix}48 &1 &6\\\\32 &5 &4\\\\16 &3 &2\\end{vmatrix}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "0",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Raman salary was decreased by 50% and subsequently increased by 50%. He has a loss of:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "0%",
            "25%",
            "0.25%",
            "2.5%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a\\space=\\space 4b\\), what percent of \\(2a\\) is \\(2b\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "10%",
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "26%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What percentage is 250 out of 1 kg?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "25%",
            "35%",
            "24%",
            "30%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The equation of the straight line passing through (2,4) and having slope -2 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2x+y=8\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2x+y=8\\)",
            "\\(2x-y=4\\)",
            "\\(x+2y=8\\)",
            "\\(x-2y=4\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A sum reckoned at 12% SI amounts to Rs. 2405 in 4 years, the sum is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1625",
        "choices": [
            "1625",
            "1635",
            "1640",
            "1652"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Ram gains the cost price of 10 books by selling 50 books. His profit percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "30%",
        "choices": [
            "30%",
            "25%",
            "20%",
            "16%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The cost price of 12 articles is equal to the selling price of 9 articles, the profit percent is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "33.33%",
        "choices": [
            "33.33%",
            "40.5%",
            "45%",
            "49%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of a triangular field whose three sides are 300, 400 and 500m (in \\(m^{3}\\)) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6000",
        "choices": [
            "6000",
            "5000",
            "400",
            "200"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The number of bricks, each \\(4cm \\times 3cm \\times 2cm\\) are required to construct a wall having the dimension \\(11cm \\times 96 \\times 64cm\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2816",
        "choices": [
            "2815",
            "2816",
            "2185",
            "2185"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The selling price of 20 articles is equal to the cost price of 20 articles. The gain percentage is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "60%",
        "choices": [
            "25%",
            "50%",
            "60%",
            "70%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\sec60^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(2\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The rate percent per annum that a sum of money trebles itself in 25 years is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "4%",
        "choices": [
            "25%",
            "10%",
            "4%",
            "8%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The present age of mother and her daughter are 30 years and 14 years respectively. The number of years ago that the product of their age was 192 is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "6",
            "7",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 5 is subtracted from the square of a number and the result is 20, the number is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\pm5\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\pm5\\)",
            "\\(\\pm6\\)",
            "\\(\\pm7\\)",
            "\\(\\pm9\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A rope is 40 ft. long is cut into two pieces. If one piece is 18 ft. longer than the other. What is the length, in feet, of the shorter piece?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "11",
        "choices": [
            "11",
            "12",
            "13",
            "14"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(M=\\begin{pmatrix}1&2\\\\2&3\\end{pmatrix},\\space M^{2}-nM-I=0\\) , the value of \\(n\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "-2",
            "-4",
            "4",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The inequality \\(-7 \\le 2x+5 \\le7\\) is equivalent to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(-6\\le x \\le 1\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(-6\\le x \\le 1\\)",
            "\\(-6 \\lt x \\lt 1\\)",
            "\\(-7\\le x\\le 5\\)",
            "\\(-6 \\le x \\le 1\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(f(x)=3x+5\\), the value of \\(\\frac{f(x+h)-f(x)}{h}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The difference of two irrational numbers is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "choices": [
            "always an irrational number",
            "always a rational number",
            "always a real number",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(p+q+r=4\\) and \\(p+q+r=8\\), the value of \\(p+r=\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "6",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(\\frac{a}{4}=\\frac{b}{5}=\\frac{c}{9}\\) then, \\(\\frac{a+b+c}{c}\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "2",
            "7",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(60\\% \\space of \\space 450=15x\\), the value of \\(x\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "18",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "18",
            "36",
            "72"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of equation \\(-4x+6y+2z=8\\) and \\(2x-3y-z=-14\\) have:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "infinitely many solutions",
        "choices": [
            "unique solution",
            "no solution",
            "infinitely many solutions",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of rectangular field is \\(493m^{2}\\) and its perimeter is 92\\(m\\), the length and breadth (in m) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "29,17",
        "choices": [
            "7,4",
            "9,7",
            "29,17",
            "19,13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "While solving the value of \\(x\\) is \\(x^{3}-3x^{2}+3x-1=0\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "1",
            "both",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sides of a triangle are 3cm, 4cm and 5cm,it is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "a right-angled triangle",
        "choices": [
            "a right-angled triangle",
            "an isosceles triangle",
            "an equilateral triangle",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which of the following represents all solutions of the inequality \\(x^{2} \\lt 2x\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(0 \\lt x \\lt 2\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(-1 \\lt x \\lt 1\\)",
            "\\(1 \\lt x \\lt 3\\)",
            "\\(0 \\lt x \\lt 2\\)",
            "\\(4 \\lt x \\lt 3\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the terms \\(2x,x+10\\space and \\space 3x+2\\) be in AP, the value of \\(x\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "7",
            "10",
            "6",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(t_{n}=3n-2\\), the value of \\(S_{5}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "35",
        "choices": [
            "35",
            "40",
            "45",
            "50"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(S_{n}=1+2+3+..........+n=20\\), the sum of the series \\(S_{n}=1^{3}+2^{3}+3^{3}+..........+n^{3}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "450",
        "choices": [
            "400",
            "500",
            "450",
            "1000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "While selling a pen for Rs. 50, there is a loss of 5%, for what price should it be sold to gain 5% ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "55.26",
        "choices": [
            "55.26",
            "55.63",
            "55",
            "56.32"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A man sold 250 chairs and had gain equal to the selling price of 50 chairs. His profit percent is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "50%",
        "choices": [
            "5%",
            "10%",
            "25%",
            "50%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A watch is bought at Rs. 250 and sold at Rs. 300, the gain percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20%",
        "choices": [
            "25%",
            "20%",
            "50%",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The list price of an article is 25% above the selling price and cost price is 40% below the list price, then rate of discount is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "40%",
        "choices": [
            "15%",
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "40%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A=\\begin{pmatrix}n& 0\\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\) and \\(A^{2}\\) is identity matrix, the value of \\(n\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "0",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(P=\\begin{pmatrix}1& 2\\\\3& -4\\end{pmatrix} \\space, \\space Q=\\begin{pmatrix}x& 3\\\\2& -1\\end{pmatrix}\\), determinant of \\(2P-3Q\\) is -5.",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{-1}{3}\\",
        "choices": [
            "\\(frac{-1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{-1}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{-1}{4}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The simple interest on Rs. 1250 for 5 years at 8% p.a. is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "500",
        "choices": [
            "480",
            "1000",
            "500",
            "625"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a sum of money doubles itself in 8 years at simple interest, the rate percent per annum is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "choices": [
            "10.5%",
            "11.5%",
            "12.5%",
            "13.5%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If two number are in the ratio \\(5:7\\) and their least common multiple is 315, their product is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2835",
        "choices": [
            "2385",
            "2538",
            "2835",
            "2583"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of the straight line that passes through the point (-1,0) and (3,8) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "6",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The probability of sample space is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The number of subsets of set of order 5 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "32",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "32",
            "8",
            "24"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{\\sqrt{9}}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "rational number",
        "choices": [
            "rational number",
            "irrational number",
            "imaginary number",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the function \\(f(x) = x^{2} - 5,\\) then \\(f(\\sqrt{5})\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "5",
            "10",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of \\(1^{st} \\space n\\) natural no. of A.P. is 55, the value of \\(n\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "10",
        "choices": [
            "10",
            "12",
            "14",
            "16"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\tan60^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{3}\\)",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If A and B are arbitary square matrices of same order, then:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((AB)^{'}=A^{'} B^{'}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((AB)^{'}=AB^{'}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{'}=A^{'} B^{'}\\)",
            "\\(A^{'}B^{'}=B^{'}A^{'}\\)",
            "\\((A+B)^{'}=A^{'}-B^{'}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A room is 12m long and 10m wide. If the area of 4 walls is \\(176m^{2}\\), the height of the room is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(4m\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(5m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(4m\\)",
            "\\(3m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(6m\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(2^{12}+2^{12}+2^{12}+2^{12}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(2^{14}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2^{14}\\)",
            "\\(4^{16}\\)",
            "\\(2^{16}\\)",
            "\\(2^{48}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If A and B are the non-singular matrices, then,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((AB)^{-1}=A^{-1}B^{-1}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((AB)^{-1}=A^{-1}B^{-1}\\)",
            "\\(AB=BA\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{1}=A^{1}B^{1}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{-1}=B^{-1}A^{-1}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is 30% of the 20% of 10% of x?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0.006x%",
        "choices": [
            "0.006x%",
            "0.6x%",
            "0.06%",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The difference between \\(\\frac{3}{5}\\) of 80 and 30% of 80 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "24",
        "choices": [
            "15",
            "10",
            "24",
            "20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "In a company with 180 employees, 108 of the employees are female. What percent of the employees of the employees are male?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "40%",
        "choices": [
            "5%",
            "25%",
            "35%",
            "40%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% p.a. is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "35 yrs",
        "choices": [
            "35 yrs",
            "70 yrs",
            "50 yrs",
            "30 yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "By selling 33m of cloth one gains the selling price of 11m. The gain percent is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "40%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "40%",
            "50%",
            "22%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Hari sold a radio for Rs. 750 with Rs. 25 loss. His loss percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3.225%",
        "choices": [
            "3.33%",
            "3.225%",
            "3.45%",
            "3.49%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Area of a rectangle is 150 sq.m. It's one side is 15m, the other side of the rectangle is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "10m",
        "choices": [
            "8m",
            "10m",
            "12m",
            "16m"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The formula to calculate the are of kite is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}d_{1} \\times d_{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}d_{1} \\times d_{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{4a}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{s(s-a)(s-b)(s-c)}\\)",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A dealer altered his trade discount from 15% to 10%, what percentage was the selling price altered ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5.88%",
        "choices": [
            "5.56%",
            "5.88%",
            "6.88%",
            "5.63%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "An article was sold for Rs. 415 at a loss of 17%, what would have been the sale price?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 500",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 475",
            "Rs. 490",
            "Rs. 500",
            "Rs. 525"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\sin135^{\\circ}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The time in .......... years that the sum of money double itself at 10% per annum of interest is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "10yrs",
        "choices": [
            "20yrs",
            "10.5yrs",
            "12yrs",
            "10yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Today is the birthday of Rahul and he is 3 times as old as Nirmala. In 13 years, Rahul will be one year less than twice as old as Nirmala will be then. The age of Rahul today is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "36 yrs",
        "choices": [
            "30 yrs",
            "36 yrs",
            "49 yrs",
            "30 yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A number consists of two digits. The sum of its digits is 16. If 18 is subtracted from the number, the digits are interchanged. The number is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "97",
        "choices": [
            "73",
            "72",
            "97",
            "24"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The breadth of a room 4m high is one third of its length. If the cost of painting its wall at the rate of Rs. 5 per \\(m^{2}\\) is Rs. 640, the cost of carpeting at the rate of Rs. 250 per \\(m^{2}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12000",
        "choices": [
            "11000",
            "12000",
            "13000",
            "14000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(7a-b=23\\) and \\(7b-a=31\\), the value of \\(a+b\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "7",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\left| (-2-3)-(-2-3) \\right |\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "4",
            "3",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(f(x)=x^{\\frac{1}{4}}+x^{\\frac{1}{2}},\\) the value of \\(f(16)\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "8",
            "32",
            "64"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which is not true?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((A+B)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((A^{T})^{T}=A\\)",
            "\\((A+B)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
            "\\((kA)^{T}=kA^{T}, \\space where \\space k \\space is \\space a \\space scalar\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of equations \\(2x+6y=6\\) and \\(6x+9y=18\\) have:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "unique solution",
        "choices": [
            "unique solution",
            "no solution",
            "infinitely many solutions",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The ratio compounded of \\(4:9\\), the duplicate ratio of \\(3:4\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5:6",
        "choices": [
            "1:4",
            "1:3",
            "3:1",
            "5:6"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x:y=6:5\\), the value of \\(\\frac{5x}{3y} : (5x-3y)\\) is equal to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5:2",
        "choices": [
            "2:1",
            "3:1",
            "5:3",
            "5:2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(5x+13=31\\), the value of \\(\\sqrt{5x+31}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "6",
            "7",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The width of a rectangle is 2cm less than its length and its length and perimeter is 12cm. The area of rectangle is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(8cm^{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(12cm^{2}\\)",
            "\\(8cm^{2}\\)",
            "\\(24cm^{2}\\)",
            "\\(18cm^{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x-7=1\\), the value of \\(x+19\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "27",
        "choices": [
            "19",
            "27",
            "38",
            "42"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The quation of the line that passes through (4, -4) and (4, 4) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(x=4\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x=4\\)",
            "\\(y=4\\)",
            "\\(y=4x\\)",
            "\\(y=4x+4\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(-7 \\le x \\le 7\\) and \\(0 \\le y \\le 12\\), the greatest possible value of \\(y-x\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "4",
            "3",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a,b,c\\) are in GP, then",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(b^{2}=ac\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(b^{2}=ac\\)",
            "\\(b(a^{2}+c^{2})=a(a^{2}+b^{2})\\)",
            "\\(b=\\frac{(a+b)}{2}\\)",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(13,p,q,r \\space and \\space 29\\) are in AP, the value of \\(p,q \\space and \\space r\\) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "none of these",
        "choices": [
            "17, 21, 25",
            "17, 22, 23",
            "11, 19, 21",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What price should a shopkeeper marks on an article, coming him Rs. 153 to gain 20%, after allowing a discount of 15%?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 216",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 224",
            "Rs. 216",
            "Rs. 154",
            "Rs. 162"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A sold an article with Rs. 250 profit which is 15% in equivalent. The cost price of the article is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 1666.67",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 1688.8",
            "Rs. 1666.67",
            "Rs. 1676.70",
            "Rs. 1677.70"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Ramita sold a skirt for Rs. 500 where she had a loss of \\(\\frac{1}{6}\\) of the cost price. The cost price of the skirt is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "600",
        "choices": [
            "605",
            "556",
            "506",
            "600"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A dealer marks his goods 60% above the cost price. What percent of discount must be allowed, if he makes a profit of 20% only ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "12%",
            "30%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 20% discount was given on math books costing Rs. 250, the selling price S.P. is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 200",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 150",
            "Rs. 100",
            "Rs. 250",
            "Rs. 200"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0 \\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\), the value of \\(A^{5}\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0 \\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0 \\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}-1& 0 \\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0 \\\\0& -1\\end{pmatrix}\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}2& -3 \\\\4& -4\\end{pmatrix}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The number of solutions \\(2x+y=4, \\space x-2y=3, \\space 3x+5y=6\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Shyam lost 15% by selling his old book for Rs. 170. For how much he must have sold it to gain 15%?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 230",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 184",
            "Rs. 194",
            "Rs. 230",
            "Rs. 224"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a plot is for Rs. 18,700, the owner losses 15%. Find the price at which it must be sold to gain 25%?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 27500",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 27000",
            "Rs. 27500",
            "Rs. 29000",
            "Rs. 38000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The selling price of four articles equals to cost price of 5 articles. The gain is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "25%",
            "28%",
            "80%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A number is divided by 10 gives a remainder 7. If the same number is divided by 5, then what will be the remainder ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one of the following value of '\\(n\\)' gives the negative result of \\(n^{2} - 15\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "7",
            "5",
            "3",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If '\\(n\\)' is an integer, then which one of the following expression must be even?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(n(n+1)\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(n(n+1)\\)",
            "\\(n^{2} + 1\\)",
            "\\(n(n+2)\\)",
            "\\(n(n+4)\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which is the sum of first five prime numbers?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "28",
        "choices": [
            "18",
            "25",
            "26",
            "28"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If you save 1 pais today, 2 paisa next day, 4 paisa the succeeding day and so on, then what is the toal saving on the week?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "127 paisa",
        "choices": [
            "127 paisa",
            "64 paisa",
            "256 paisa",
            "128 paisa"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 6 is subtracted from the cube of a number and the result is 21, then what is the value of that number?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the product of two consecutive even number is 288, then what are these numbers from following?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "16, 18",
        "choices": [
            "14, 12",
            "14, 16",
            "16, 18",
            "22, 24"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The total of ages of A and B is 3:5, if B is 8 years elder to A, then what is the age of the A ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12 yrs",
        "choices": [
            "12 yrs",
            "15 yrs",
            "18 yrs",
            "21 yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the root of the equation \\(x^{2}-6x+c=0\\) is 3, then what is the value of \\(c\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "9",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "6",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one of the following is true for the roots of the equation \\(x^{2}-8x+16=0\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "real & equal",
        "choices": [
            "imaginary & unequal",
            "rational & unequal",
            "real & equal",
            "real & unequal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the matrix is of order \\(5 \\times 3\\), then how many elements will be single column?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "3",
            "4",
            "15"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x-5 = 1\\), then what is the value of \\(x+7\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "13",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "7",
            "8",
            "13"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(5x+13=31\\), what is the value of \\(\\sqrt{(5x+31)}\\) ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "6",
            "7",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the correct value of \\(\\frac{5^{4}-5^{3}}{4}\\).",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(5^{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(5^{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{5}\\)",
            "\\(5^{4}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{5}{4}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a^{x}=b, \\space b^{y}=c \\space and \\space c^{z}=a\\), then what is the value of \\(xyz\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(1\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(c\\)",
            "\\(a\\)",
            "\\(b\\)",
            "\\(1\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(p+q=r,\\) then what is the average value of \\(p, q, \\space r\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{2r}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{r}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{(p+q)}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2r}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{r}{3}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the slope of the line whose equation is \\(2x-4y=9?\\)",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "equal",
        "choices": [
            "complementary",
            "supplementary",
            "adjacent",
            "equal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "There are 60 students in a class. If 60% of them are girls, then how many boys in the class ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "24",
        "choices": [
            "24",
            "36",
            "18",
            "40"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Last year Hari was 4 feet tall, and this year he is 5 feet tall. What is the percent increase of his height ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "25%",
        "choices": [
            "10%",
            "15%",
            "20%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the difference between \\(\\frac{3}{5} \\space of \\space 80\\) and 30% of 80 ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "24",
        "choices": [
            "12",
            "18",
            "24",
            "20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The cost of 6 pens is equal to the cost of the 10 pencils. If the cost of 4 pencils is Rs. 120, then what is the cost of 4 pens ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "200",
        "choices": [
            "100",
            "200",
            "300",
            "400"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the cost of 7 kg sugar is Rs. 210, how much sugar can be purchased for Rs. 330?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "11 kg",
        "choices": [
            "11 kg",
            "12 kg",
            "13 kg",
            "14 kg"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Ganga can read 48 pages per hour. At this rate, how many pages she can read in 80 minutes ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "64",
        "choices": [
            "60",
            "72",
            "48",
            "64"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Two numbers are in the ratio of 6:7 and their sum is 117, then what are these numbers?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "54, 63",
        "choices": [
            "56, 58",
            "63, 54",
            "54, 63",
            "48, 56"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(5:7=15:x\\), then what is the value of \\(x\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "21",
        "choices": [
            "18",
            "21",
            "24",
            "35"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If cost price of 8 pens and selling price of 10 pens is equal, then what is loss percentage?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "15%",
            "10%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the 20% discount is given on computer book costing Rs. 300, then what will be selling price?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 240",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 240",
            "Rs. 220",
            "Rs. 260",
            "Rs. 250"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A watch is bought of Rs. 250 and sold at Rs. 300, then what is the profit percentage?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20%",
        "choices": [
            "10%",
            "15%",
            "20%",
            "25%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% per annum ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "30 yrs",
        "choices": [
            "60 yrs",
            "50 yrs",
            "40 yrs",
            "30 yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the rate percentage per annum that a sum of money trebles itself in 25 years ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2%",
        "choices": [
            "2%",
            "4%",
            "6%",
            "8%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the cardinal number of a vowel set \\(V = \\left\\{ a,e,i,o,u \\right\\}\\) ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "5",
            "6",
            "7"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the minimum value of \\(n(P \\cap Q)\\)? When \\(n(U)=100, n(P)=70, \\space and \\space n(Q)=45\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "15",
        "choices": [
            "15",
            "55",
            "30",
            "45"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one of the following is true for prime number?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "only two factors",
        "choices": [
            "no factors",
            "only one factor",
            "only two factors",
            "more than two factors"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one of the following interval notation is correct for \\(\\left\\{x:5 \\le x \\le 15 \\right\\}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\left [5, 15 \\right ]\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left [5, \\infty \\right ]\\)",
            "\\(\\left [\\infty, 14 \\right ]\\)",
            "\\(\\left [6, 13 \\right]\\)",
            "\\(\\left [5, 15 \\right ]\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of '\\(x\\)' when it is multiplied by 6 and added to 3 times its own number gives 63?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "7",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\((\\sqrt{5}+\\sqrt{5})^{2}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20",
        "choices": [
            "20",
            "25",
            "10",
            "60"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the number of seconds in \\(1 \\frac{1}{3}\\) hour ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "4800 sec",
        "choices": [
            "1200 sec",
            "2400 sec",
            "3600 sec",
            "4800 sec"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "In a kilometer race A beats B by 100 meters and B beats C by 150 meters. In the same race, by how many meters does A beats C?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "250 m",
        "choices": [
            "150 m",
            "100 m",
            "250 m",
            "200 m"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of 4 walls of square room is \\(120m^{2}\\). If the height is \\(5m\\), then what is the area of its floor?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(36 m^{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(26 m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(56 m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(25 m^{2}\\)",
            "\\(36 m^{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the probability of death ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "0",
            "\\(\\infty\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the chance to give the birth by a pregnant lady on Tuesday ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{7}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{3}{7}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{7}\\)",
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the BACHELOR is written as 12345678, then how will BCA be written?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "132",
        "choices": [
            "123",
            "432",
            "147",
            "132"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Saru ranks \\(8^{th}\\) from the top and \\(20^{th}\\) from the bottom in class, then how many students are there in class room ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "27",
        "choices": [
            "28",
            "27",
            "20",
            "29"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Find the value of '\\(x\\)' in series \\(1,1,2,3,5,8,13,x\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "21",
        "choices": [
            "21",
            "22",
            "23",
            "20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\(\\cos0^{\\circ}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
            "0",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the slope of line joining (1,2) and (k,-5) is equally inclined with both the axes, then the value of k is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "-6",
            "3",
            "-2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\(\\cot90^{\\circ}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "0",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the probability of drawing a queen when one card is drawn randomly from a well shuffled pack of 52 cards? Find the probability of drawing a red queen?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{26}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{26}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{5}{6}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{3}{4}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{15}{36}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A, B, C\\) are the subsets of a universal set \\(U\\). Then \\(A-(B \\cup C)\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((A-B) \\cap (A-C)\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((A-B) \\cup (A-C)\\)",
            "\\((A-B) \\cap (A-C)\\)",
            "\\((A \\cap B) - (A \\cap C)\\)",
            "\\((A \\cup B) - (A \\cup C)\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Of a group of 120 students, 90 takes mathematics and 72 takes statistics. If 10 students neither of two, the number of student taking both subjects are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "52",
        "choices": [
            "50",
            "45",
            "52",
            "58"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(-5 \\lt x \\lt 7\\) can be written in the absolute value sign as:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\left | x - 1 \\right | \\lt 6\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left | x -1 \\right | \\lt 7\\)",
            "\\(\\left | x - 1 \\right | \\lt 6\\)",
            "\\(\\left | x - 1 \\right | \\lt 2\\)",
            "\\(\\left | x - 1 \\right | \\lt -1\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the relation \\(R = \\left\\{ (1,2),(2,3),(3,4),(4,5) \\right\\}\\) then its range is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\left\\{ 2,3,4,5 \\right\\}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left\\{ 2,3,4,5 \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\left\\{ 1,2,3,4 \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\left\\{ 1,2,3,5 \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\left\\{ 1,3,4,5 \\right\\}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\tan180^{\\circ}\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "-1",
            "0",
            "\\(\\infty\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(1^{2}+2^{2}+3^{2}+..........+n^{2}\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}{6}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{n(n+1)}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{n(n+1)(2n+1)}{6}\\)",
            "\\(\\left [\\frac{(n+1)}{2} \\right]^{2}\\)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a matrix \\(A = \\begin{pmatrix}0& 5& -6\\\\-5& 0& 2\\\\6& -2& 0\\end{pmatrix}\\), then matrix \\(A\\) is known as",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Skew-Symmetric Matrix",
        "choices": [
            "Symmetric Matrix",
            "Skew-Symmetric Matrix",
            "Diagonal Matrix",
            "Triangular Matrix"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The radius of the circle \\(x^{2}+y^{2}=9\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "3",
            "5",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(2\\sqrt{128} + \\sqrt{162}\\) is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(25 \\sqrt{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(25 \\sqrt{2}\\)",
            "\\(4 \\sqrt{3}\\)",
            "0",
            "60"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = \\begin{bmatrix}1& 2\\\\3&1\\end{bmatrix}\\), then the value of \\(A^{2}-2A-5I\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "-1",
            "2",
            "0"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the half of quarter of 400 ?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "50",
        "choices": [
            "200",
            "100",
            "50",
            "90"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Half percent, written as a decimal is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0.005",
        "choices": [
            "0.2",
            "0.02",
            "0.005",
            "0.05"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The true discount on Rs. 2,562 due 4 months hence is Rs. 122. The rate percent is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "14%",
        "choices": [
            "12%",
            "13%",
            "14%",
            "15%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The percentage increase in the area of a rectangle, if each of its sides is increased by 20% is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "44%",
        "choices": [
            "40%",
            "42%",
            "44%",
            "46%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "AB and CD bisect each other at O. If AD = 6cm, BC is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6cm",
        "choices": [
            "5.9cm",
            "6cm",
            "4.8cm",
            "7cm"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The compound interest on Rs. 30,000 at 7% per annum is Rs. 4347. The period (in years) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "3",
            "4",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a man were to sell his chair Rs. 720, he would lose 25% to gain 25%. He would sell it for:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 1,200",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 1,200",
            "Rs. 1,000",
            "Rs. 960",
            "Rs. 900"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Find the percentage gain or loss when the dot pens bought for Rs. 96 per dozen were sold at the rate of 10 for Rs. 90?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12.5%",
        "choices": [
            "13%",
            "20%",
            "4%",
            "12.5%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the value of \\(\\cos^{2}30^{\\circ}-\\sin^{2}30^{\\circ}\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{-1}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "How many stones each of area \\(0.16 cm^{2}\\) are required for paving a courtyard 5.5m long and 4.8m wide?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "165",
        "choices": [
            "60",
            "100",
            "50",
            "165"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one is the formula for area of equilateral triangle?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "None of these",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{4a^{2}}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2} \\times b \\times h\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{(s-a)(s-b)(s-c)}\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The commission of Rs. 5,600 at the rate of 3.5% is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 196",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 196",
            "Rs. 440",
            "Rs. 360",
            "Rs. 1,000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The discount percent of marked price is Rs. 5,800 and discount amount is Rs. 696 then the discount percent is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12%",
        "choices": [
            "12%",
            "20%",
            "5%",
            "38%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is the tax rate if original price is Rs. 2,000 and selling price is Rs. 2,400?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "20%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "17.39%",
            "35%",
            "10%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of the ages of father and his son is 52 years. Eight years ago the father was eight times as old as his son, the present age of son is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12 years",
        "choices": [
            "10 years",
            "20 years",
            "12 years",
            "15 years"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If 4 is subtracted from a square of a number, its result is 21. The number is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "4",
            "6",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The radius of the circle \\(x^{2}+y^{2}-12x-4y=9\\) is equal to,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "18",
            "7",
            "10",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of linear equation will be consistent and independent if they have,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "exactly one solution",
        "choices": [
            "exactly one solution",
            "more than one solution",
            "no solution",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Let \\(a\\) and \\(b\\) are two numbers on the real line. If \\((a, b) = \\left\\{ x:a \\lt x \\le b \\right\\}\\) is known as,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "open interval",
        "choices": [
            "left open interval",
            "right open interval",
            "closed interval",
            "open interval"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Let \\(f:R \\to R \\space and \\space g(x):R \\to R\\) be defined by \\(f(x)=2x^{2}-3, \\space g(x)=3x+2\\). Then the composite functions \\(g_{\\circ}f(x)\\) is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(6x^{2}-7\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(9x+8\\)",
            "\\(2x+2\\)",
            "\\(2x+1\\)",
            "\\(6x^{2}-7\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A square matrix A is said to be singular if its determinant is equal to",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "0",
            "-1",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of equations \\(4x - 3y = -6, \\space -4x+2y=16\\) is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "consistent and independent",
        "choices": [
            "consistent and dependent",
            "inconsistent and independent",
            "inconsistent and dependent",
            "consistent and independent"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Ratio of 2km to 600m should be,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "10:3",
        "choices": [
            "2:7",
            "2:8",
            "2:3",
            "10:3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a:b=c:d\\), then \\(b\\) and \\(c\\) are called,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "extreme",
        "choices": [
            "antecedent",
            "extreme",
            "consequent",
            "mean"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(b^{2}-4ac \\lt 0\\) then the roots of \\(ax^{2}+bx+c=0\\) are:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "imaginary",
        "choices": [
            "equal",
            "rational",
            "irrational",
            "imaginary"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A polygon having 10 sides is called,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "decagon",
        "choices": [
            "decagon",
            "heptagon",
            "quadrilateral",
            "hexagon"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Linear equation is also known as,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "first degree equation",
        "choices": [
            "simultaneous equation",
            "second degree equation",
            "first degree equation",
            "zero degree equation"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Two straight lines in same plane which never meet are called,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "parallel line",
        "choices": [
            "angles",
            "transversal lines",
            "vertex",
            "parallel line"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x^{4}-3x+5\\) is divided by \\(2x-1\\), then remainder is,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{-35}{16}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{35}{16}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{-35}{16}\\)",
            "-9",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A, G, H\\) are arithmetic, geometric and harmonic means between \\(a \\space and \\space b\\),",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "real numbers",
        "choices": [
            "in G.P.",
            "in A.P",
            "real numbers",
            "in H.P."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "In selling an article for Rs. 76, a shopkeeper gain 53%. The gain by selling that for Rs. 74 is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "49%",
        "choices": [
            "45%",
            "48%",
            "49%",
            "50%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Ram bought oranges at 6 for Rs. 10 and sold them at 4 for Rs. 6, find his loss percent",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "8%",
        "choices": [
            "12%",
            "8%",
            "6%",
            "10%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which of the following is incorrect?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(A.M = ab\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(A.M = ab\\)",
            "\\(G.M = \\frac{2ab}{a+b}\\)",
            "\\(H.M = \\frac{a+b}{2}\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "By giving a discount of 10% on the marked price of Rs. 1,100 of a mobile phone a dealer gains 10%, then the cost price is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "Rs. 900",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 950",
            "Rs. 900",
            "Rs. 1,000",
            "Rs. 1,050"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Rama purchased a table in Rs. 1,260 and due to some damage on its top, she had to sell it for Rs. 1,197,",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "5%",
        "choices": [
            "20%",
            "15%",
            "10%",
            "5%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = \\begin{pmatrix}1& 0& 0\\\\0& 1& 0\\\\0 & 0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\), then \\(A\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "unit matrix",
        "choices": [
            "unit matrix",
            "singular matrix",
            "symmetric",
            "all of them are true"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The slope of the straight line that passes through the point (-1, 0) and (3, 8) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "2",
            "4",
            "6",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the function \\(f(x)=x^{2}-5\\), then \\(f(\\sqrt{5}\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "5",
            "10",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The sum of \\(1^{st} \\space n\\) natural number of A.P. is 55, the value of \\(n\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "10",
        "choices": [
            "10",
            "12",
            "14",
            "16"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If A and B are arbitrary square matrices of same order, then:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\((AB)^{'}=A^{'}B^{'}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((AB)^{'} = AB^{'}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{'}=A^{'}B^{'}\\)",
            "\\(A^{'}B^{'}=B^{'}A^{'}\\)",
            "\\((A+B)^{'}=A^{'}-B^{'}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "What is 30% of the 20% of 10% of \\(x\\)?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(0.6x\\%\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(0.006x\\%\\)",
            "\\(0.6x\\%\\)",
            "\\(0.06%\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The difference between \\(\\frac{3}{5} \\space of \\space 80\\) and 30% of 80 is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "24",
        "choices": [
            "15",
            "10",
            "24",
            "20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "In a company with 180 employees, 108 of the employees are female. What percent of the employees are male?",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "40%",
        "choices": [
            "5%",
            "25%",
            "35%",
            "40%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The population doubling time if the population growth rate is 2% p.a is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "35yrs",
        "choices": [
            "35yrs",
            "70yrs",
            "50yrs",
            "30yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "He sold a radio for Rs. 750 with Rs. 25 loss. His loss percentage is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "3.225%",
        "choices": [
            "3.33%",
            "3.225%",
            "3.45%",
            "3.49%"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Area of a rectangle is \\(150m^{2}\\). It's one side is \\(15m\\), the height of the rectangle is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(10m\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(8m\\)",
            "\\(10m\\)",
            "\\(12m\\)",
            "\\(16m\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The formula to calculate the area of kite is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2} \\times d_{1} \\times d_{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2} \\times d_{1} \\times d_{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{4a}\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{s(s-a)(s-b)(s-c)}\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Today is the birthday of Rahul and he is 3 times as old as Nirmala. In 13 years, Rahul will be one year less than twice as old as Nirmala will be then. The age of Rahul today is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "33yrs",
        "choices": [
            "33yrs",
            "36yrs",
            "49yrs",
            "30yrs"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The breadth of a room \\(4m\\) high is one third of its length. If the cost of painting its wall at the rate of Rs. 5 per \\(m^{2}\\) is Rs. 640, the cost of carpeting at the rate of Rs. 250 per \\(m^{2}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "12000",
        "choices": [
            "11000",
            "12000",
            "13000",
            "14000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(7a-b=23 \\space and \\space 7b-a=31\\), the value of \\(a+b\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "9",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "7",
            "8",
            "9"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\left |(-2-3)-(-2-3) \\right| \\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "0",
            "3",
            "2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(f(x)=x^{\\frac{1}{4}}+x^{\\frac{1}{2}}\\), the value of \\(f(16)\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "6",
            "8",
            "32",
            "64"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of equations \\(2x+6y=6 \\space and \\space 6x+9y=18\\) have:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "unique solution",
        "choices": [
            "unique solution",
            "no solution",
            "infinitely many solutions",
            "none of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x:y=6:5\\), the value of \\((5x+3y):(5x-3y)\\) is equal to:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(3:1\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2:1\\)",
            "(\\3:1\\)",
            "\\(5:3\\)",
            "\\(5:2\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The equation of the line that passes through (4,-4) and (4,4) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\(x=4\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x=4\\)",
            "\\(y=4\\)",
            "\\(y=4x\\)",
            "\\(y=4x+4\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(-7 \\le x \\le 7 \\space and \\space 0 \\le y \\le 12\\), the greatest possible value of \\(y-x\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "19",
        "choices": [
            "16",
            "17",
            "18",
            "19"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = \\begin{pmatrix}1& 0\\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}\\), the value of \\(A^{5}\\) is",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0\\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}",
        "choices": [
            "\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0\\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}",
            "\\begin{pmatrix}-1& 0\\\\0& 1\\end{pmatrix}",
            "\\begin{pmatrix}1& 0\\\\0& -1\\end{pmatrix}",
            "\\begin{pmatrix}2& -3\\\\4& -4\\end{pmatrix}"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The number of solutions of \\(2x+y=4, 3x+5y=6\\) is:",
        "programme": "BCA",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 50
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word that express the meaning of BRIEF",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Limited",
        "choices": [
            "Limited",
            "Small",
            "Little",
            "Short"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word that express the meaning of DISTANT",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Far",
        "choices": [
            "Far",
            "Removed",
            "Reserved",
            "Seperared"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word that express the meaning of FAKE",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Imitation",
        "choices": [
            "Original",
            "Imitation",
            "Trustworthy",
            "Loyal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word that express the meaning of ALERT",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Watchful",
        "choices": [
            "Energetic",
            "Observant",
            "Intelligent",
            "Watchful"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word with the opposite meaning of the word ARTIFICIAL",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Nautral",
        "choices": [
            "Red",
            "Natural",
            "Truthful",
            "Solid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word with the opposite meaning of the word EXPAND",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Condense",
        "choices": [
            "Condense",
            "Convert",
            "Congest",
            "Conclude"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word with the opposite meaning of the word BUSY",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Relaxed",
        "choices": [
            "Occupied",
            "Engrossed",
            "Relaxed",
            "Engaged"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word with the opposite meaning of the word FRESH",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Stale",
        "choices": [
            "Faulty",
            "Stale",
            "Sluggish",
            "Disgraceful"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "The dog barked .......... the stranger.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "upon",
            "over",
            "at",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "You must bear .......... my weakness.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "with",
        "choices": [
            "up",
            "with",
            "in",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "A blind man is no judge .......... colours.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "for",
            "in",
            "of"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "My friends is not accustomed .......... drinking.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "with",
            "in",
            "to",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "List of the business or subjects to be considered at a meeting.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Agenda",
        "choices": [
            "Agenda",
            "Time table",
            "Plan",
            "Schedule"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Leave or remove from a place considered dangerous.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Evacuate",
        "choices": [
            "Evade",
            "Evacuate",
            "Avoid",
            "Exterminate"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "One who possesses many talents.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Versatile",
        "choices": [
            "Gifted",
            "Nubile",
            "Exceptional",
            "Versatile"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Something that will last forever.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Eternal",
        "choices": [
            "Celestial",
            "Godly",
            "Eternal",
            "Repetitive"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Where is the headquater of UNESCO?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Paris",
        "choices": [
            "New York",
            "New Delhi",
            "Nairobi",
            "Paris"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Highest speed of wind could be expected in case of",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Hurricane",
        "choices": [
            "Strong breeze",
            "Strong storm",
            "Hurricane",
            "Strong gale"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "The longest river of the world",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Nile",
        "choices": [
            "Indus",
            "Nile",
            "Ganga",
            "Amazon"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following name is asociated with aircraft?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Wirght Brothers",
        "choices": [
            "Marconi",
            "Peter Paul",
            "Wirght Brothers",
            "James Watt"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following arilines does not have regular passenger flights to Kathmandu?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "JAL",
        "choices": [
            "JAL",
            "Korean Air",
            "Bangladesh Biman",
            "Qatar Airways"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "A websites main page is called:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Home page",
        "choices": [
            "Website page",
            "Home page",
            "Search page",
            "Browser page"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Mona Lisa is known for",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Painting",
        "choices": [
            "Dancing",
            "Cooking",
            "Rafting",
            "Painting"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Data that is copied from application is stored in the",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Clipboard",
        "choices": [
            "RAM",
            "Prompt",
            "Clipboard",
            "CPU"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which among the following is the most common source of viruses to the hard disk of your computer?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Incoming Email",
        "choices": [
            "Incoming Email",
            "Outgoing Email",
            "CDROM",
            "Websites"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Bulls and bears are the terms associated with",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Stock exchange",
        "choices": [
            "Parliamentary affairs",
            "Stock exchange",
            "Bull fights",
            "Racing"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "With which of the following items is the trade name CG group of industries associated?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Instant noodles",
        "choices": [
            "Cement",
            "Blades",
            "Instant noodles",
            "Tractors"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Tikapur is on the bank of river",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Karnali",
        "choices": [
            "Karnali",
            "Mahakali",
            "Gandaki",
            "Koshi"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "The first man to set foot on the moon was",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Neil Armstrong",
        "choices": [
            "Robert Crippen",
            "Alexei Leonov",
            "Yuri Gagarin",
            "Neil Armstrong"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the folloiwing is not a himalayan river?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Bagmati",
        "choices": [
            "Trishuli",
            "Bagmati",
            "Kali Gandaki",
            "Koshi"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Siesmology refers to",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Earthquakes",
        "choices": [
            "Earthquakes",
            "Plants",
            "Humidity",
            "Planets"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Oslo is the capital of",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Norway",
        "choices": [
            "Norway",
            "Canada",
            "Yaman",
            "Sweden"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Silver fish is",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "An insect",
        "choices": [
            "A fish",
            "An insect",
            "A term used in politics",
            "A fish made of silver"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following place is not on the direct bus route from Bharatpur to Janakpur?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Hetauda",
        "choices": [
            "Birgunj",
            "Hetauda",
            "Nijgarh",
            "Bardibas"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Swargadwari Temple is situated in",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Pyuthan",
        "choices": [
            "Surkhet",
            "Jajarkot",
            "Dang",
            "Pyuthan"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Mahabharata was written by",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Ved Vyas",
        "choices": [
            "Ved Vyas",
            "Manu",
            "Surdas",
            "Tulsidas"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Where is the headquarter of UNESCO ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Paris",
        "choices": [
            "New York",
            "New Delhi",
            "Nairobi",
            "Paris"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "The longest river in the world is",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Nile",
        "choices": [
            "Indus",
            "Nile",
            "Ganga",
            "Amazon"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following airlines does not have regular passenger flights to Kathmandu ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "JAL",
        "choices": [
            "JAL",
            "Korean Air",
            "Bangladesh Biman",
            "Qatar Airways"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following name is associated with aircraft ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Wright brothers",
        "choices": [
            "Marconi",
            "Peter Paul",
            "Wright brothers",
            "James Watt"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "A web sites main page is call as",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Home page",
        "choices": [
            "Website page",
            "Home page",
            "Search page",
            "Browser page"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which among the following is the most common source of viruses to the hard disk of your computer ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Incoming Email",
        "choices": [
            "Incoming Email",
            "Outgoing Email",
            "CD-ROM",
            "Websites"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "With which of the following items is the trade name CG Group of Industries associated ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Cement",
        "choices": [
            "Cement",
            "Blades",
            "Instant noodles",
            "Tractors"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Tikapur is on the banks of river",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Karnali",
        "choices": [
            "Karnali",
            "Mahakali",
            "Gandaki",
            "Koshi"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a Himalayan river ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Bagmati",
        "choices": [
            "Trishuli",
            "Bagmati",
            "Kali Gandaki",
            "Koshi"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Seismology refers to",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Earthquakes",
        "choices": [
            "Earthquakes",
            "Plants",
            "Humidity",
            "Planets"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Awareness",
        "question": "Which of the following place is not on the direct bus route from Bharatpur to Janakpur ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Hetauda",
        "choices": [
            "Birgunj",
            "Hetauda",
            "Nijgrah",
            "Bardibas"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "What is the full form of WTO?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "World Travel Organization",
        "choices": [
            "World Travel Organization",
            "Wimbeldon Tennis Office",
            "World Trade Organization",
            "Women Travel Organization"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following can be considered as seasonal industry?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Sugar",
        "choices": [
            "Cement",
            "Sugar",
            "Automobile",
            "Power"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following is Nepal's largest trading partner?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "USA",
            "Japan",
            "China",
            "India"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Cheap money policy is adopted generally during",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Recession",
        "choices": [
            "Boom",
            "Hyper inflation",
            "Inflation",
            "Recession"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following will not be considered investment?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Piling of inventories on a trader's shelf",
        "choices": [
            "Piling of inventories on a trader's shelf",
            "The building of a school",
            "Construction of a house",
            "Purchase of 100 shares of Standard Chartered Bank"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "The regulators authority for stock market in Nepal is",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Nepal Stock Exchange",
        "choices": [
            "Nepal Stock Exchange",
            "Nepal Rastra Bank",
            "Company Registra's Office",
            "Ministry of Finance"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Profit margins are the lowest in",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Perfect competition",
        "choices": [
            "Absolute monopoly",
            "Monopolistic competition",
            "Oligopolistic competition",
            "Perfect competition"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following payment instruments is known as plastic money?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Credit cards",
        "choices": [
            "Bearer cheques",
            "Demand drafts",
            "Credit cards",
            "Gift cheques"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "VAT is a/an",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Sales tax",
        "choices": [
            "Income tax",
            "Sales tax",
            "Custom duty",
            "Travel tax"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Globalization refers to:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "A more integrated and interdependent world",
        "choices": [
            "Lower incomes worldwide",
            "Less foreign trade and investment",
            "Global warming and their effects",
            "A more integrated and interdependent world"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Whose signature are found on thousand rupee note of Nepal",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Governor, NRB",
        "choices": [
            "Minister of finance",
            "Governor, NRB",
            "Prime Minister",
            "Secretary, Ministry of Finance"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Accounting is the process of matching",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Revenue and costs",
        "choices": [
            "Benefits and costs",
            "Revenue and costs",
            "Cash inflow and outflows",
            "Potential and real performance"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristics of monopoly?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Product differentiation",
        "choices": [
            "Product differentiation",
            "Only onr producer",
            "Large profit margins",
            "Ineffiencies"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "What is SWOT analysis?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Strength, Weakness, Opportunity and Threat",
        "choices": [
            "Swift Work of Tribes",
            "Sustainable Work of Transport",
            "Strength, Opportunity, Weakness and Threat",
            "Strength, Weakness, Opportunity and Threat"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following ratio inicates the finnancial risk of a firm?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Debt equity ratio",
        "choices": [
            "Market yeild",
            "Dividend cover",
            "Debt equity ratio",
            "Net profit margin"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Net worth means",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Paid up capital + free reserves - accumulated losses",
        "choices": [
            "Paid up capital + free reserves",
            "Paid up capital",
            "Paid up capital - accumulated losses",
            "Paid up capital + free reserves - accumulated losses"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following districts of Nepal is the largest producer of coffee?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Ilam",
        "choices": [
            "Surkhet",
            "Gulmi",
            "Bhktapr",
            "Ilam"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which country is known as the world's sugar bowl",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "Cuba",
            "China",
            "USA",
            "India"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "What is the full form of WTO ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "World Trade Organization",
        "choices": [
            "World Travel Organization",
            "Wembledon Tennis Office",
            "World Trade Organization",
            "Women Travel Organization"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following can be considered as seasonal industry ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Sugar",
        "choices": [
            "Cement",
            "Sugar",
            "Automobile",
            "Power"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following is Nepal's largest trading partner ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "India",
        "choices": [
            "USA",
            "Japan",
            "China",
            "India"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "The regulatory authority for stock markets in Nepal is",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Securities Board of Nepal",
        "choices": [
            "Securities Board of Nepal",
            "Nepal Rastra Bank",
            "Ministry of Finance",
            "Company Registrar's Office"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Whose signatures are found on thousand rupee note of Nepal ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Governor, NRB",
        "choices": [
            "Minister of Finance",
            "Governor, NRB",
            "Prime Minister",
            "Secretary, Ministry of Finance"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Accounting is the process of matching:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Revenue and costs",
        "choices": [
            "Benefits and costs",
            "Revenue and costs",
            "Cash inflows and outflows",
            "Potential and real performance"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a characteristic of monopoly ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Product differentiation",
        "choices": [
            "Product differentiation",
            "Only one producer",
            "Large profit margins",
            "Inefficiencies"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "What is SWOT analysis ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Strength, Weakness, Opportunity and Threat",
        "choices": [
            "Swift Work of Tribes",
            "Sustainable Work of Transport",
            "Strength, Opportunity, Weakness and Threat",
            "Strength, Weakness, Opportunity and Threat"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following ratio indicates the financial risk of a firm ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Debt equity ratio",
        "choices": [
            "Market yield",
            "Dividend cover",
            "Debt equity ratio",
            "Net profit margin"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following is an unfavorable condition for economic development ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "High inflation rate",
        "choices": [
            "Low interest rate",
            "High inflation rate",
            "High industrial production",
            "a & b"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Risk that is associated with a stock is usually measured in terms of",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Beta",
        "choices": [
            "Beta",
            "Variance",
            "Standard Deviation",
            "Total returns"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Business and Economics",
        "question": "Which of the following districts of Nepal is the largest producer of coffee ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Illam",
        "choices": [
            "Surkhet",
            "Gulmi",
            "Bhaktapur",
            "Illam"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "A vendor bought toffees at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "4",
            "5",
            "6"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Which of the following number is a perfect square ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "7744",
        "choices": [
            "7799",
            "7755",
            "7766",
            "7744"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "If the digits of the numbers 5 7 2 6 4 8 9 are arranged in ascending order, how many digits will remain at the same position?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Three",
        "choices": [
            "None",
            "One",
            "Two",
            "Three"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "If 6 is 24% of a number, what is 40% of the same number?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "10",
        "choices": [
            "8",
            "10",
            "15",
            "20"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "A salary of an officer being increased by 10% every year becomes Rs 48400 in the third year. What was his original salary?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Rs 40000",
        "choices": [
            "Rs 45000",
            "Rs 44000",
            "Rs 42000",
            "Rs 40000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "60 is 80% of which number ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "75",
        "choices": [
            "60",
            "72",
            "75",
            "80"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "When 10,000 increased by 0.1%, we get",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "10100",
        "choices": [
            "10001",
            "10010",
            "10100",
            "11000"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Which of the following numbers is divisible by 12 but not by 8?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "108",
        "choices": [
            "72",
            "88",
            "108",
            "120"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "The average of \\(x\\) and \\(y\\) is 40. If \\(z = 10\\), what is the average of \\(x\\), \\(y\\) and \\(z\\)?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "30",
        "choices": [
            "16.6",
            "20",
            "25",
            "30"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "What is the 0.5% of 100,000?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "500",
        "choices": [
            "0.05",
            "0.50",
            "50",
            "500"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "If a sum of money is divided equally among \\(n\\) children, each child will receive Rs 60. If another child is added to the group, then when the sum is divided equally among all children, each child will receive a Rs 50 share. What is the sum of money?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Rs 300",
        "choices": [
            "Rs 100",
            "Rs 120",
            "Rs 300",
            "Rs 400"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "A vendor bought bananas at 6 for a rupee. How many for a rupee must he sell to gain 20%?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "5",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "4",
            "5",
            "6"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "If there are 5 routes for travelling between two places A and B, how many option are there for a person to travel from A to B and return back?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "25",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "10",
            "9",
            "25"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "A student has an average of 86 in three examinations. What grade must he/she receive on his/her next test to raise his/her average to 88?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "94",
        "choices": [
            "94",
            "90",
            "92",
            "100"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "If \\(8x + 4 = 32\\), then \\(2x - 1 = ?\\)",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "6",
        "choices": [
            "9",
            "8",
            "6",
            "5"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "The simplest interest on Rs 600 at 6% for six months is",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Rs 18",
        "choices": [
            "Rs 218",
            "Rs 21.80",
            "Rs 36",
            "Rs 18"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Find odd one out: 4, 8, 12, 18, 36, 54, 108",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "18",
        "choices": [
            "8",
            "12",
            "18",
            "36"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Find odd one out: 10, 25, 45, 54, 60, 75, 80",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "54",
        "choices": [
            "10",
            "45",
            "54",
            "75"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Find odd one out: 3, 5, 11, 14, 17, 21",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "14",
        "choices": [
            "21",
            "17",
            "14",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Quantitative Ability",
        "question": "Find odd one out: 1, 4, 9, 16, 23, 25, 36",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "23",
        "choices": [
            "9",
            "23",
            "25",
            "36"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Library : Books ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "School : Student",
        "choices": [
            "School : Student",
            "CDO : Criminal",
            "Forest : Trees",
            "Gentlemen : Meeting"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Sugar : Sweet ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Wine : Grapes",
        "choices": [
            "Ice : Cold",
            "Butter : Cow",
            "Attack : Fail",
            "Wine : Grapes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Biratnagar : Morange ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Birgunj : Parsa",
        "choices": [
            "Kathmandu : Nepal",
            "Butwal : Bhairahawa",
            "Birgunj : Parsa",
            "Bharatpur : Ratnanagar"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Ink : Paper ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Chalk : Blackboard",
        "choices": [
            "Door : Handle",
            "Dog : Tail",
            "Chalk : Blackboard",
            "Speak : Sing"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Doctor : Lawyer ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Patient : Client",
        "choices": [
            "Client : Illness",
            "Patient : Medicine",
            "Medicine : Fee",
            "Patient : Client"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Select the pair of words which expresses the relationship similar to that expressed: Bee : Hive ::",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Mouse : Hole",
        "choices": [
            "People : Meeting",
            "River : Stream",
            "Mouse : Hole",
            "Fry : Cook"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "556",
        "choices": [
            "221",
            "333",
            "556",
            "777"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Research Scholar",
        "choices": [
            "Research Scholar",
            "Lecturer",
            "Headmaster",
            "Principal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Tansen",
        "choices": [
            "Tansen",
            "Dhangadi",
            "Nepalgunj",
            "Nagarkot"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Six",
        "choices": [
            "Half",
            "Quarter",
            "One-third",
            "Six"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Colombo",
        "choices": [
            "London",
            "New York",
            "Colombo",
            "Jakarta"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "112",
        "choices": [
            "91",
            "112",
            "135",
            "154"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Choose the word which is least like other words in a group:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Careful",
        "choices": [
            "Bagful",
            "Careful",
            "Skillful",
            "Hopeful"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If 6145 stands for FADE and 9451 stands for IDEA, what does 8978 stand for ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "HIGH",
        "choices": [
            "THIS",
            "NIGH",
            "HIGH",
            "THAT"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If BAD is coded as YZW and FIGHT is coded as URTSG, then HIGH will be coded as",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "SRTS",
        "choices": [
            "PRSP",
            "TRST",
            "RSTR",
            "SRTS"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If \\(2 \\times 3 = 812\\), and \\(4 \\times 5 = 1620\\) then \\(6 \\times 7 =\\)",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "2428",
        "choices": [
            "6677",
            "6767",
            "2428",
            "2824"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If LN NP QS DF stands for MORE, then SU QS TV SU GI stands for",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "TRUTH",
        "choices": [
            "FRUIT",
            "FAITH",
            "TRUTH",
            "TREES"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I like .......... in my spare time.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "reading",
        "choices": [
            "reading",
            "read",
            "to read",
            "to reading"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I went to the bookshop .......... 'Harry Potter'.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "to buy",
        "choices": [
            "for buying",
            "to buy",
            "to buying",
            "for to buy"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He is interested .......... learning Romanian.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "in",
        "choices": [
            "in",
            "on",
            "to",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Would you like .......... to drink, Sir?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "anything",
        "choices": [
            "anything",
            "anywhere",
            "nothing",
            "something"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What .......... next weekend?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "are you doing",
        "choices": [
            "do you do",
            "are you doing",
            "will you do",
            "did you do"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "How manu students in your class .......... from Bangladesh?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "come",
        "choices": [
            "comes",
            "come",
            "came",
            "are coming"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am hungry. I want two .......... of chicken.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "pieces",
        "choices": [
            "plates",
            "pieces",
            "bowls",
            "gasses"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "They are ugly and expensive, .......... people buy them.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "still",
        "choices": [
            "although",
            "yet",
            "still",
            "besides"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What time ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "does the train leave?",
        "choices": [
            "the train leaves?",
            "is the train leaving?",
            "leaves the train",
            "does the train leave?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I promise I .......... study harder.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "will",
        "choices": [
            "will",
            "am going to",
            "may",
            "must"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "How long .......... English?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "have you been learning",
        "choices": [
            "are you learning",
            "have you been learning",
            "do you learn",
            "you learn"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I hope that a school .......... for village children.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "opens",
        "choices": [
            "opens",
            "is opened",
            "has to be opened",
            "be opened"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest similar meaning of word 'demolish' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "destroy",
        "choices": [
            "repair",
            "consume",
            "humiliate",
            "destroy"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest similar meaning of word 'beneficent' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "veracity",
        "choices": [
            "mandatory",
            "untruthfulness",
            "veracity",
            "potential"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest opposite meaning of word 'theocracy' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "secularism",
        "choices": [
            "secularism",
            "ideology",
            "conservative",
            "chruch state"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest similar meaning of word 'compunction' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "remorse",
        "choices": [
            "remorse",
            "recklessness",
            "merciful",
            "connive"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest opposite meaning of word 'integrate' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "segregate",
        "choices": [
            "accomodate",
            "segregate",
            "compose",
            "articulate"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest opposite meaning of word 'Calm' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "excited",
        "choices": [
            "excited",
            "restful",
            "cool",
            "serene"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Closest meaning of word 'wordy' is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "rambling",
        "choices": [
            "rambling",
            "concise",
            "diffuse",
            "voluble"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A teacher needs to discuss in classes, it .......... curiosity in students.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "creates",
        "choices": [
            "creates",
            "created",
            "create",
            "will create"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Successful people always .......... two things: one, determination and second,sincerity.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "have",
        "choices": [
            "had",
            "doing",
            "did",
            "have"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "They like swimming, whenever they have a leisure time.(which word is not a verbal noun?)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "free",
        "choices": [
            "Leisure",
            "free",
            "like",
            "swimming"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Nobody likes heap of garbage in front of his house.(Which word is a collective noun?)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "heap of garbage",
        "choices": [
            "heap of garbage",
            "in front",
            "house",
            "likes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is noun?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "reality",
        "choices": [
            "real",
            "readable",
            "reliable",
            "reality"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "English is today the third .......... native language worldwide after Chinese and Hindi with some 380 million speakers.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "most spoken",
        "choices": [
            "the most spoken",
            "the more spoken",
            "much spoken",
            "most spoken"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We could barely get aby information at the airport .......... people seemd to have .......... idea about the flights.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Few/no",
        "choices": [
            "Many/any",
            "A lot of/any",
            "Few/no",
            "Only a few/some"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... his friends speaks any English.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Neither of",
        "choices": [
            "Some",
            "All",
            "Many",
            "Neither of"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "These differeneces between two photographs .......... with the help of Photoshop.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "could have been remove",
        "choices": [
            "should remove",
            "have to remove",
            "could have been remove",
            "must have removed"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "New legislation .......... in congress but it .......... by any.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "was introduced/wasn't accepted",
        "choices": [
            "was introduced/wasn't accepted",
            "was introduced/didn't accept",
            "is introduced/won't accept",
            "introduced/hadn't been accepted"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Mike has been told he will have to pay the fine .......... his high rank in the military.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "despite",
        "choices": [
            "even if",
            "furthermore",
            "despite",
            "on purpose that"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The economy in China is booming; .......... many foreign investors are planning to enter China's market.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "so as to",
        "choices": [
            "Nonetheless",
            "so as to",
            "in addition to",
            "that's why"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I wish you .......... making that noise. It's bothering me.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "would stop",
        "choices": [
            "would stop",
            "are going to stop",
            "stop",
            "can stop"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... more help, I could call my neighbour.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Should I need",
        "choices": [
            "Needed",
            "Should I need",
            "I have needed",
            "I should need"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "If you plan to take a long trip in the car, you must get a full tank of gas or you .......... out of gas.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "might run",
        "choices": [
            "hve to run",
            "should have to run",
            "had better run",
            "might run"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "If you want to get a good night's sleep, you .......... any tea or coffee in the evenings",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "mustn't drink",
        "choices": [
            "would rathe drink",
            "don't have to drink",
            "mustn't drink",
            "not able to drink"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "It is not easy for many civil servants to .......... on their salaries as the inflation rate is extremely high.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "get by",
        "choices": [
            "get by",
            "turn up",
            "wear out",
            "run over"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I thought the party was going to be boring, nut it .......... to be the most unforgettable evening of my life.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "turned out",
        "choices": [
            "turned out",
            "looked around",
            "passed away",
            "fell back on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I like reading .......... in my spare time.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "reading",
        "choices": [
            "reading",
            "read",
            "to read",
            "to reading"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Could you .......... these paper.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "clear up",
        "choices": [
            "clear out",
            "clear away",
            "clear up",
            "clear off"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I am going to .......... a house that I'm thinking of buying.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "look into",
        "choices": [
            "look on",
            "look through",
            "look over",
            "look into"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "You can not ride or drive safely before he has been ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "broken in",
        "choices": [
            "break down",
            "break off",
            "broken in",
            "break out"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We had to .......... dried milk as fresh milk wasn't available.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "fall back on",
        "choices": [
            "fall back on",
            "fall back",
            "fall in",
            "fall off"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He is a pleasant friendly man who .......... well with nearly everybody.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "get on",
        "choices": [
            "get over",
            "get round",
            "get off",
            "get on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A scientific method of photostatting is ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Zeroxography",
        "choices": [
            "Zeroxography",
            "photography",
            "orthography",
            "lithography"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Morbid fear of everything in general is ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "pathophobia",
        "choices": [
            "pathophobia",
            "hippophile",
            "dendrophile",
            "xenophobia"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Lover of trees is called ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "dendrophile",
        "choices": [
            "podophile",
            "hippophile",
            "dendrophile",
            "paedophile"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Hater of knowledge ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "misologist",
        "choices": [
            "pacifist",
            "iconoclast",
            "misogynist",
            "misologist"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the right synonym of the word \"magniloquent\"",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "boastful",
        "choices": [
            "boastful",
            "sentimental",
            "mournful",
            "venal"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the right synonym of \"pellucid\"",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "transparent",
        "choices": [
            "dark",
            "transparent",
            "dim light",
            "vague"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The antonym of \"alienate\" is ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "reconcile",
        "choices": [
            "social",
            "alleviate",
            "transfer",
            "reconcile"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the right antonym of \"wanton\"",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "retrained",
        "choices": [
            "retrained",
            "reckless",
            "unruly",
            "vagabond"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The .......... of these roses is sweet. The .......... of burning rubber is unbearable.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "smell, stink",
        "choices": [
            "scent, perfume",
            "perfume, scent",
            "smell, stink",
            "stink, smell"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "One who plays for pleasure is ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "amateur",
        "choices": [
            "fanatic",
            "amateur",
            "egoist",
            "feminist"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "One who abandons his/her religious faith:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "apostate",
        "choices": [
            "heuristic",
            "fanatic",
            "agnostic",
            "apostate"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A person who is hard to please ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "fastidious",
        "choices": [
            "fastidious",
            "taciturn",
            "stubborn",
            "hednoist"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "John is born .......... highly educated parents.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "of",
            "by",
            "for",
            "from"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We can travel .......... car or walk .......... feet or go .......... horseback.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "by, on, on",
        "choices": [
            "by, on, on",
            "for, by, on",
            "on, by, on",
            "on, on, on"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Lucky was fined .......... parking his vehicle .......... a no parking area.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "for, in",
        "choices": [
            "in, for",
            "for, in",
            "ar, for",
            "for, with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Nobody knew the way .......... except John.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "except",
        "choices": [
            "besides",
            "but",
            "except",
            "beside"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He would think it .......... him to tell a lie.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "behind",
        "choices": [
            "above",
            "beside",
            "behind",
            "opposite"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... doing the cooking, I help hostel boys.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "besides",
        "choices": [
            "besides",
            "beside",
            "behind",
            "opposite"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Peter hardly goes to parties, ..........?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "does he?",
        "choices": [
            "doesn't he",
            "does he?",
            "did he?",
            "didn't he?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ann'll lend it you, Oh no, ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "she won't",
        "choices": [
            "she'll",
            "she can't",
            "she won't",
            "she did"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Everyone warned you, ..........?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "didn't they?",
        "choices": [
            "have they?",
            "haven't they",
            "didn't they?",
            "did they?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He had no qualification; .......... he got the job.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "nevertheless",
        "choices": [
            "however",
            "in spite of",
            "though",
            "nevertheless"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What does \"be neck and neck\" stand for?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "equally good in competiton",
        "choices": [
            "equally good in competiton",
            "be good friends",
            "great enemies",
            "ready for competition"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "As a beginner in Panish class I could not stand the pace.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "maintain the level",
        "choices": [
            "could not learn",
            "maintain the level",
            "very weak",
            "not fit for the class"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He is the friend .......... I trust most in family matters.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "whom",
        "choices": [
            "who",
            "whom",
            "which",
            "him"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Public often .......... people who are good at sport.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "admire",
        "choices": [
            "attract",
            "appeal",
            "admire",
            "support"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Choose the word with correct spelling:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "foreign",
        "choices": [
            "forin",
            "foraign",
            "foreign",
            "forigin"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "In the word \"transcendental\" which syllable has the primary stress:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "3rd syllable",
        "choices": [
            "1st syllable",
            "2nd syllable",
            "3rd syllable",
            "4th syllable"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I was invited to .......... dinner given to welcome te new ambassador.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "the",
        "choices": [
            "a",
            "the",
            "an",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He goes to .......... temple sometimes to give lectures,",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "the",
        "choices": [
            "a",
            "the",
            "an",
            "none"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He has worked for us ever .......... he left school.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "since",
        "choices": [
            "from",
            "during",
            "for",
            "since"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Every rational number is also",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "a real number",
        "choices": [
            "a natural number",
            "an integer",
            "a whole number",
            "a real number"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(a - ib = \\frac{3-2i}{3+2i}\\) then \\(a^{2}+b^{2} =\\)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "1",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{4}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{3}{5}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2}{9}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(Given \\space U = \\left\\{1,2,3,..........,14 \\right\\}, \\space A= \\left\\{x:x \\le 8 \\right\\}, \\space B= \\left\\{x:x \\ge 4 \\right\\} \\space then \\space \\overline{A \\cap B} =\\)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "None of these",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\phi\\)",
            "\\(U\\)",
            "\\(A \\cup B\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which are the equal ordered pairs?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\((2,4),(4,2)\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((2,4),(4,2)\\)",
            "\\((2,2),(4,4)\\)",
            "\\((4,2),(4,2)\\)",
            "All of them"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(S_{\\infty}=\\frac{a}{1-r}\\), when \\(a, \\space r \\space \\& \\space S_{\\infty}\\) denotes first term, common ratio and sum to infinity. If",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\left |r \\right | \\lt 1\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\left |r \\right | \\lt 1\\)",
            "\\(\\left | r \\right | \\gt 1\\)",
            "\\(\\left |r \\right | = 1\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(^{21}C_{x}=^{21}C_{y}\\) then which is true?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(x \\neq y\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x \\neq y\\)",
            "\\(x = y\\)",
            "\\(x+y=21\\)",
            "either (b) or (c)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which is not true?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\((A+B)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((A^{T})^{T}=A\\)",
            "\\((A+B)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{T}=A^{T}B^{T}\\)",
            "\\((AB)^{T}=B^{T}A^{T}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one is not true ?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}& a_{2}& a_{3}\\\\0& 0& 0\\\\c_{1}& c_{2}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix} = 0\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}& a_{2}& a_{3}\\\\b_{1}& b_{2}& b_{3}\\\\c_{1}& c_{2}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix} = \\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}& b_{1}& c_{1}\\\\a_{2}& b_{2}& c_{2}\\\\a_{3}& b_{3}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix}\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{vmatrix}0& a_{2}& a_{3}\\\\b_{a}& 0& b_{3}\\\\c_{1}& c_{2}& 0\\end{vmatrix}=0\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}& a_{2}& a_{3}\\\\0& 0& 0\\\\c_{1}& c_{2}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix} = 0\\)",
            "\\(\\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}& b_{1}& c_{1}\\\\a_{2}& b_{2}& c_{2}\\\\a_{3}& b_{3}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix} = \\begin{vmatrix}a_{1}+ka_{3}& b_{1}+kb_{3}& c_{1}+kc_{3}\\\\a_{2}& b_{2}& c_{2}\\\\a_{3}& b_{3}& c_{3}\\end{vmatrix}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The equation \\(x=0\\) represents",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(y-axis\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x-axis\\)",
            "\\(y-axis\\)",
            "the origin",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The angle between the lines \\(xy=0\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(90^{\\circ}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(0^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(60^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(90^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(120^{\\circ}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which one is correct ?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(log_{10} \\space ^{10}=1\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(log_{10} \\space ^{1}=0\\)",
            "\\(log_{10} \\space ^{0.1}=-1\\)",
            "\\(log_{10} \\space ^{10}=1\\)",
            "All of them"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The domain of \\(y = f(x) = \\frac{1}{x}\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(R - \\left\\{0 \\right\\}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(R - \\left\\{0 \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(R\\)",
            "\\((-2,1)\\)",
            "\\((-1,1)\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Let \\(f:R \\to R\\) be defined by \\(f(x)=10x-7\\) then \\(f^{-1}(x)\\)=",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{x+7}{10}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{10x+7}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{10x-7}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{x+7}{10}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{x-7}{10}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(t\\) be a positive real number then the least value of \\(t + \\frac{1}{t}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "4",
            "3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The value of \\(\\lim_{x \\to \\infty} \\frac{\\sqrt{x+1}}{\\sqrt{x} + 1}\\) is:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "0",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "-1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The point of discontinuity of the function \\(f(x)= \\frac{x^{3} - 27}{x-3}\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "3",
        "choices": [
            "3",
            "6",
            "27",
            "0"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x+y = xy\\) then \\(\\frac{dy}{dx}=\\)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{y-1}{1-x}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{x-1}{y-1}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{y-1}{1-x}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1-x}{y-1}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1+y}{1-x}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(x=2at, \\space y=at^{2}\\) then \\(\\frac{dy}{dx}=\\)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(t\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(t\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{t}\\)",
            "\\(t^{2}\\)",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the total cost function \\(C=50x+5000\\). The marginal cost function \\(MC\\) is:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "50",
        "choices": [
            "\\(50+\\frac{5000}{x}\\)",
            "\\(25x^{2}+5000x\\)",
            "50",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The maximum value of \\(\\sin \\theta cos \\theta \\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The function \\(f(x)=2-3x\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "decreasing",
        "choices": [
            "decreasing",
            "increasing",
            "neither decreasing nor increasing",
            "doesn't exist"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\int_{-2}^{2} \\left| \\space x \\space \right|\\space dx\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the marginal cost of a product is given by \\(MC = 8 + 6x - 3x^{2}\\) and the fixed cost is Rs. 150. The cost function is:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(8x+3x^{2}-x^{3}+150\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(8x+6x^{x}-6x^{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{8}{x}+6-3x\\)",
            "\\(8x+3x^{2}-x^{3}+150\\)",
            "\\(8x+3x^{2}-x^{3}-150\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area of the circle \\(x^{2}+y^{2}=16\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(16 \\pi \\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(4 \\pi \\)",
            "\\(4 \\pi ^{2}\\)",
            "\\(16 \\pi ^{2}\\)",
            "\\(16 \\pi \\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which is the measure of dispersion?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "range",
        "choices": [
            "mean",
            "median",
            "mode",
            "range"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Two brothers: Mr. X and Mr. Y appear in an interview for getting the scholarship. The scholarship can be provided for two persons. The probability of getting scholarship by Mr. X is \\(\\frac{1}{7}\\) and getting by Mr. Y is \\(\\frac{1}{5}\\). What is the probability that both of them will get scholarship?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{35}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{12}{35}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{35}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{23}{35}\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The equation \\(\\sinx+\\cosx=2\\) has",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "no solution",
        "choices": [
            "infinite solution",
            "finite solution",
            "no solution",
            "unique solution"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\sin^{-1}x + \\cos^{-1}x = \\)",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "None",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{x}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{-\\pi}{x}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{x} - x\\)",
            "None"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The system of linear equations \\(2x+3y=5 \\space and \\space 4x+6y=9\\) are",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "inconsistent & independent",
        "choices": [
            "consistent & dependent",
            "consistent & independent",
            "inconsistent & independent",
            "inconsistent & dependent"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The degree of polynomial equation \\(ax^{2}+bx+c=0\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "2",
        "choices": [
            "0",
            "1",
            "2",
            "not define"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If one root of a quadratic equation in the real coefficient is \\(\\sqrt{2}\\) then equation is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(x^{2}-2=0\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x^{2}+\\sqrt{2}x+2=0\\)",
            "\\(x^{2}+2=0\\)",
            "\\(x^{2}-2=0\\)",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The equation \\(x^{2}+y^{2}=0\\) represents",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "degenerate circle",
        "choices": [
            "circle",
            "degenerate circle",
            "an empty set",
            "a straight line"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If four quantities \\(a, \\space b, \\space c \\space and \\space d\\) are such that \\(a:b=3:4, \\space b:c=6:7 \\space and \\space c:d=8:9\\), then the ratio between \\(a\\) and \\(d\\) is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "4:7",
        "choices": [
            "3:8",
            "1:3",
            "4:7",
            "7:4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "By selling 175 pens, a stationary store gains the selling price of 50 pens. What is his gain percent?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "40%",
        "choices": [
            "40%",
            "\\(28 \\frac{4}{7}\\)",
            "50%",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A, B, C and D enter into a partnership. A, B, C subscribe \\(\\frac{1}{3}, \\frac{1}{4}, \\frac{1}{5}\\) of the capital respectively and D, the rest. What is the share of profit of D if the total profit is Rs. 24600?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Rs. 5330",
        "choices": [
            "Rs. 8200",
            "Rs. 5330",
            "Rs. 6150",
            "Rs. 4920"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If US $1 = Rs. 78.15. How many US dollars are equivalent to Rs. 10,000?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "$127.96",
        "choices": [
            "$127.96",
            "$172.96",
            "$196.72",
            "$172.62"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The effective rate corresponding to 10% p.a. convertible quarterly is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "10.4%",
        "choices": [
            "40%",
            "10.1%",
            "10.4%",
            "None of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The present value of an immediate annuity is; where symbols are there usual meaning",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{p}{i} \\left\\{l - \\frac{l}{(l+i)^{n}} \\right\\}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{p}{i} \\left\\{(l+i)^{n} - l \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{p}{i} (l+i) \\left\\{(l+i)^{n}-l \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{p}{i} \\left\\{l - \\frac{l}{(l+i)^{n}} \\right\\}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{p(l+i)}{i}\\left\\{ l \\space - \\frac{l}{\\left( l+i \\right)^{n}} \\right\\}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The study of sound & sound waves is known as ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Acoustics",
        "choices": [
            "Mechanical",
            "Technical",
            "Acoustics",
            "Sound waves"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "A river always has",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Banks",
        "choices": [
            "Delta",
            "Fishes",
            "Boats",
            "Banks"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which mountain is understood by 'Killer Mountain'?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Naga Parbat",
        "choices": [
            "Manaslu",
            "Ama Dablam",
            "Naga Parbat",
            "Kala Patthar"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which of the following is necessary for 'knowledge'?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Learning",
        "choices": [
            "School",
            "Teacher",
            "Text Book",
            "Learning"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Two concepts are related in some way; establish the same relationship on the basis of the alternatives given for UTS:FDS::WVU?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "WXY",
        "choices": [
            "YWV",
            "WXY",
            "UVW",
            "HGF"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Insert the appropriate arithmetical signs in (?,?) to establish the relation: 9?6?3=27",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "+,*",
        "choices": [
            "+,*",
            "=,+",
            "/,+",
            "+,+"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If LIGHT is coded as GLITH, find the code for RAINY.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "ARINY",
        "choices": [
            "IARYN",
            "ARINY",
            "NAIRY",
            "RINAY"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "A,B and C are intelligent, A, D and E are laborious, D, C and E are honest and A, B, and E are ambitious. Which of the following are not honest?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "C and A",
        "choices": [
            "A and B",
            "C and A",
            "A and D",
            "A and B"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Analog computer work on the supply of",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "continous electrical pulse",
        "choices": [
            "physical strength",
            "natural strength",
            "magnetic strength",
            "continous electrical pulse"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "We can make use of the wild card entries such as.......... in Windows Explorer.",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "^,*",
        "choices": [
            "#,@",
            "^,*",
            "?,*",
            "?,#"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which of the following is the second largest measurement of RAM?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Gigabyte",
        "choices": [
            "Megabyte",
            "Gigabyte",
            "Byte",
            "Terabyte"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Cache memory acts between",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "CPU and RAM",
        "choices": [
            "CPU and Hard disk",
            "RAM and ROM",
            "CPU and RAM",
            "ALl of these"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Whcih of the billionth of a sceond?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Nanosecond",
        "choices": [
            "Microsecond",
            "Nanosecond",
            "Terabyte",
            "Gigabyte"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The Binary Coded Decimal uses",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "8 bits",
        "choices": [
            "6 bits",
            "8 bits",
            "16 bits",
            "32 bits"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "RAM is also called as",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "volatile memory",
        "choices": [
            "virtual memory",
            "volatile memory",
            "non volatile memory",
            "cache memory"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "CPU stands as",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Central Processing Unit",
        "choices": [
            "Central Processing Unit",
            "Computer Processed Unity",
            "Computer Pro Unit",
            "Cache Processing Unit"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If you want to copy a portion of the text then you need to use",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Control and C",
        "choices": [
            "Control and C",
            "Command and C",
            "Contorl and V",
            "Control and X"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which one is not an operating system?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "LaTex",
        "choices": [
            "Windows",
            "Linux",
            "Unix",
            "LaTex"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Who described his policy of unification as one of 'blood and iron'?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Bismarck",
        "choices": [
            "Hitler",
            "Mazzini",
            "Napoleon",
            "Bismarck"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Who is known as the father of Modern Medicine?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Hippocrates",
        "choices": [
            "Eratosthenes",
            "Euclid",
            "Pythagoras",
            "Hippocrates"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which of the following is the place of worship for Judaism?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Synagogue",
        "choices": [
            "Temple",
            "Fire Temple",
            "Chapel",
            "Synagogue"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The hottest planet of the solar system is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Venus",
        "choices": [
            "Mercury",
            "Venus",
            "Mars",
            "Jupiter"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The first word pronounced at the surface of the Moon during Apollo Expedition is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "OK!",
        "choices": [
            "OK!",
            "YES!",
            "Hurry!",
            "Fine!"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The longest district of Nepal is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Juddha Samsher",
        "choices": [
            "Kavrepalanchowk",
            "Sindhupalchowk",
            "Parsa",
            "Juddha Samsher"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Which of the person had divided Nepal into 32 distict",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Juddha Samsher",
        "choices": [
            "Chandra Samsher",
            "Ranoddip",
            "Bir Samsher",
            "Juddha Samsher"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The longest glacier of Nepal is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Khumbu",
        "choices": [
            "Khumbu",
            "Lamtang",
            "Upper Arun",
            "Kanchanjangha"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "Rawan of epic Ramayana had written two books. The name of one of those books is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Arkapakshya",
        "choices": [
            "Arkapakshya",
            "Rawapakshya",
            "Manupakshya",
            "Kiwapakshya"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "General Knowledge + Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "The founder of Tao Religion is",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Laotse",
        "choices": [
            "Kanfusius",
            "Laotse",
            "Ding",
            "Fung"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Which of the following is not a search engine?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Altavista",
        "choices": [
            "Google",
            "Altavista",
            "Yahoo",
            "Firefox Mozilla"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Name of the screen that recognizes touch input is:",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Touch screen",
        "choices": [
            "Recog screen",
            "Point screen",
            "Touch screen",
            "Andriod screen"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Arranage in ascending order the units of memory TB, KB, Gb, MB",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "TB>GB>MB>KB",
        "choices": [
            "TB>MB>GB<KB",
            "MB>GB>TB>KB",
            "TB>GB>MB>KB",
            "GB>MB>KB>TB"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "What is the full form of WWW?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "World Wide Web",
        "choices": [
            "World Wide Web",
            "Wide World Web",
            "World Web Wide",
            "Wide Wide World"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Junk email is also called",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Spam",
        "choices": [
            "Spam",
            "Spoof",
            "Sniffer",
            "Jmail"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Which of the following is used to make presentation slides?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Powerpoint",
        "choices": [
            "Powerpoint",
            "Word",
            "Excel",
            "Internet"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Who is the father of computer?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Charles Babbage",
        "choices": [
            "Charles Babbage",
            "Balise Pascal",
            "Garden Moore",
            "John Von Neumann"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "Which of the following is used as a memory in computers?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "RAM",
        "choices": [
            "RAM",
            "Keyboard",
            "Mouse",
            "Mouse"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "MS-Word is an example of ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Application software",
        "choices": [
            "Operating system",
            "Application software",
            "Output device",
            "Processing device"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "IT general",
        "question": "The printed output drom a computer is known as ..........",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Soft copy",
        "choices": [
            "Soft copy",
            "Hard copy",
            "Photo copy",
            "Paper"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 10
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... his project was not completed, he was given permission to leave.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Although",
        "choices": [
            "Although",
            "in spite of",
            "as it",
            "despite"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Rajendra is .......... had working and friendly.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "but also",
        "choices": [
            "but also",
            "both",
            "as well as",
            "not only"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "More than one hundred people .......... to the meeting.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "have come",
        "choices": [
            "have come",
            "has come",
            "is coming",
            "was coming"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Mr. Thakuri speaks both Nepali .......... Maithali very prefectly",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "as well as",
        "choices": [
            "as well as",
            "and also",
            "and",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Reading, observing, teaching and .......... are good ways to gain knowledge.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "discussion",
        "choices": [
            "discussion",
            "discussing",
            "to discuss",
            "discusing"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The river Narayani flow thorugh .......... Narayanghat.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "no article",
        "choices": [
            "an",
            "a",
            "the",
            "no article"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "In recent years people have been more concerned .......... quality of driking water.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "with",
            "for",
            "about",
            "of"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She was killed .......... a robber .......... A gun.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "by; with",
        "choices": [
            "by; for",
            "by; with",
            "in; for",
            "with; for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The fear of rape and robbing .......... caused many people run away from the cities.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "has",
        "choices": [
            "has",
            "have",
            "was",
            "has been"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The grass needs ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "to be cut",
        "choices": [
            "cutting",
            "to cut",
            "to be cut",
            "both a and b"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": ".......... this evidence, I know, he is in the right.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "from",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "from",
            "by",
            "in"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I object .......... your propos",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "about",
            "in",
            "to"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I have worked .......... the answer.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "out",
        "choices": [
            "about",
            "over",
            "among",
            "out"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which word doesn't take .......... is suffix?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "history",
        "choices": [
            "history",
            "athlete",
            "artist",
            "success"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following does not take a prefix?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "provided",
        "choices": [
            "provided",
            "poisonous",
            "protected",
            "detected"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is a verb?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "spectacular",
        "choices": [
            "spectacular",
            "marvel",
            "comparable",
            "fancy"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We shall finish worked before he ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "will come",
        "choices": [
            "will come",
            "would come",
            "could come",
            "comes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The memoranda .......... approved.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "is",
        "choices": [
            "is",
            "was",
            "has been",
            "have been"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which is incorrect?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "forceps",
        "choices": [
            "scissors",
            "tweezers",
            "forceps",
            "pincers"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Lack of blood ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "anemia",
        "choices": [
            "amnesia",
            "insomnia",
            "anemia",
            "epicurean"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A well experienced person is ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "lawyer",
        "choices": [
            "lawyer",
            "cosmopolitian",
            "veteran",
            "teacher"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The doubt .......... Gita will come.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "if",
        "choices": [
            "that",
            "if",
            "when",
            "why"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "They walk very fast. The underlined work is..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "adverb",
        "choices": [
            "adverb",
            "adjective",
            "preposition",
            "demonstrative adjective"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The passiven of: They heard me sing a song.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "I washeard singing a song",
        "choices": [
            "I was heard to sing a song",
            "I was heard sing a song",
            "I washeard singing a song",
            "I was heard to sing a song by them"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The indirect of: He said, 'Congratulation'.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "He sai that congratulations.",
        "choices": [
            "He sai that congratulations.",
            "he congratulated me",
            "he congratulated that I passed.",
            "He said that i deserved congratulations."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The word \"education\" has the stress on the .......... syllable.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "first",
        "choices": [
            "first",
            "second",
            "thord",
            "fourth"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Select the rght synonym to the word \"adrous\"",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Simple",
        "choices": [
            "Simple",
            "Difficult",
            "easy",
            "strange"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give the opposite meaning of \"obscure\"",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Pedantic",
        "choices": [
            "Pedantic",
            "impllicit",
            "expilict",
            "obnoxious"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The initial consonant sound of \"chef\" is the same as that of ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Chute",
        "choices": [
            "Chute",
            "chess",
            "child",
            "cheap"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I completely differ .......... you .......... this point.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "From: at",
        "choices": [
            "From: at",
            "from: in",
            "from: on",
            "to:at"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "We feel sympathy .......... the poor.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "with",
            "about",
            "for"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "He insisted .......... leaving immediately.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "at",
        "choices": [
            "at",
            "in",
            "on",
            "over"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Food that agree to one's taste is ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "pungent",
        "choices": [
            "pungent",
            "edible",
            "palatable",
            "suspicious"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The word \"pleased\" takes the prefix ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "un-",
        "choices": [
            "un-",
            "mis-",
            "dis-",
            "none-"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Fear of food is called as ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Sitophobia",
        "choices": [
            "Sitophobia",
            "ergophobia",
            "Panthophobia",
            "hyctophobia"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A funeral bell is called",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "call",
        "choices": [
            "call",
            "knell",
            "replica",
            "invitation"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "People .......... a large number of computers now, because prices are getting low.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "must buy",
        "choices": [
            "must buy",
            "must have bought",
            "must be buying",
            "must buying"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Although they are similar, chipmunks are .......... most other ground squirrels.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "alike",
        "choices": [
            "alike",
            "like as",
            "like to",
            "like"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She .......... the whole day long.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Has been working",
        "choices": [
            "Has been working",
            "works had worked",
            "works",
            "worked"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Now a days Shyam is .......... busy to take care of his health.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "very",
        "choices": [
            "very",
            "to",
            "so",
            "extremely"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "She demanded .......... her status.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "know",
        "choices": [
            "know",
            "knwoing",
            "to know",
            "to be known"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "The mail comes ar ten O'clock everday .......... saturday.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "But also",
        "choices": [
            "But also",
            "and",
            "also",
            "but"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "In my office, salary is paid by .......... month.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "the",
        "choices": [
            "the",
            "a",
            "an",
            "some"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Ever boy and every girl .......... very responsible.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "are",
        "choices": [
            "are",
            "is",
            "has",
            "have"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is an adjective?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "sympathize",
        "choices": [
            "sympathize",
            "lighten",
            "preception",
            "moral"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is accepted?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Some of rice is still left",
        "choices": [
            "Some of rice is still left",
            "Time and tide wait for none",
            "She absents herself from the college today",
            "None of the squares was properly drawn"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Which of the following words is a synonym for \"exquisite\" ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Beautiful",
        "choices": [
            "Beautiful",
            "Mediocre",
            "Ugly",
            "Average"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Choose the word that is most opposite in meaning to \"brave\":",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Timid",
        "choices": [
            "Timid",
            "Fearless",
            "Bold",
            "Valiant"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "Identify the correctly spelled word:",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Conscious",
        "choices": [
            "Consciouss",
            "Consciouos",
            "Conscious",
            "Consciuos"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Verbal Ability",
        "question": "She was .......... to attend the party because she had a prior commitment.",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Unable",
        "choices": [
            "Eligible",
            "Unable",
            "Willing",
            "Obligated"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "John is taller than Mark, and Mark is taller than Tim. Who among them is the shortest ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "Insufficient information",
        "choices": [
            "John",
            "Mark",
            "Tim",
            "Insufficient information"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "All cats are mammals, and all mammals have four legs. What can we conclude from these statements ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "All cats have four legs",
        "choices": [
            "All cats have four legs",
            "All animals with four legs are cats",
            "Some mammals have four legs",
            "Some cats are not mammals"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "A company conducted a survey to determine the popularity of its products among different age groups. The results showed that 60% of respondents were aged between 18 and 35, and the remaining respondents were aged 36 or above. If the company received a total of 500 responses, how many respondents were aged 36 or above ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "300",
        "choices": [
            "200",
            "250",
            "300",
            "350"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If it rains, then the ground is wet.\nWhich of the following can be concluded from the statement ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "If the ground is wet, then it must have rained.",
        "choices": [
            "If the ground is wet, then it is raining.",
            "If it is not raining, then the ground is not wet.",
            "If the ground is wet, then it must have rained.",
            "If it is not raining, then the ground is wet."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Logical Reasoning",
        "question": "If it snows, then the temperature is below freezing. \nWhich of the following statements can be logically inferred from the given statement ?",
        "programme": "BIM",
        "answer": "If the temperature is above freezing, then it is not snowing.",
        "choices": [
            "If the temperature is above freezing, then it is not snowing.",
            "If it is snowing, then the temperature is below freezing.",
            "If the temperature is below freezing, then it is snowing.",
            "If it is not snowing, then the temperature is above freezing."
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 20
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the sum of two angles is \\(90^{\\circ}\\) and one angle is \\(35^{\\circ}\\), what is the measure of the other angle ?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "\\(45^{\\circ}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(45^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(55^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(65^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(80^{\\circ}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If a triangle has sides of lengths 5, 12, and 13, what type of triangle is it ?",
        "programme": "BIT",
        "answer": "Right triangle",
        "choices": [
            "Equilateral triangle",
            "Isosceles triangle",
            "Scalene triangle",
            "Right triangle"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 40
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Number of non-empty singleton subsets from the elements of the set \\(\\left\\{ 1, \\space m, \\space n, \\space p \\right\\} is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "4",
            "3",
            "2",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Left \\(f: A \\to B \\), then \\(f\\) is invertible if",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(f\\) is both one-one and onto",
        "choices": [
            "\\(f\\) is one-one",
            "\\(f\\) is onto",
            "\\(f\\) is both one-one and onto",
            "\\(f\\) is one-one into"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Let \\(f: R \\to R\\) be defined by \\(f(x) = 3x-4\\), then \\(f^{-1}(x)\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{x+4}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{x+4}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{x-4}{3}\\)",
            "\\(x+4\\)",
            "\\(x-4\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\lim_{x\\to\\infty}\\left( 1+\\frac{3}{x} \\right)^{x}\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(e^{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(e^{3}\\)",
            "\\(3e\\)",
            "\\(3e^{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{e^{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\frac{d}{dx}\\left( \\log\\left| \\space x \\space \\right| \\right)\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{x}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{\\abs{x}}\\)",
            "\\(\\pm \\frac{1}{x}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{x}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{x^{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Derivative of \\(\\sin^{3}x\\) w.r.t. \\(\\cos^{3}x\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "None of these options",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\tan x\\)",
            "\\(-\\tan x\\)",
            "\\(\\tan^{3}x\\)",
            "None of these options"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(f(x)=\\log (\\log x)\\), then \\(f^{-1}(e)\\)",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(e^{e}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(e\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{e}\\)",
            "\\(e^{e}\\)",
            "-1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The minimum value of \\(f(x)=\\sin x. \\cos x\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(-\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "0",
            "1"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\int_{}{\\log x dx}\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\((x(\\log x-x)+C\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((\\log x-1)+C\\)",
            "\\((x(\\log x-x)+C\\)",
            "\\((x \\log x + 1)+C\\)",
            "\\((x (\\log x - 1) + C\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\int_{0}^{\\frac{\\sqrt{3}}{2}}\\frac{dx}{\\sqrt{1} - x^{2}}\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{4}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The area bounded by the parabola \\(y^{2}=x\\), the line \\(y=4\\) and y-axis is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{64}{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{16}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{32}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{64}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{128}{3}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The modulus of \\(\\frac{(1-i)^{3}}{1-i^{3}}\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "-1",
            "\\(i\\)",
            "\\(\\sqrt{2}\\)",
            "-2"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The roots of the equation \\(2x^{2}-3x+1=0\\) are",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "real, unequal",
        "choices": [
            "real, unequal",
            "real, equal",
            "perfect square, equal",
            "unequal, imaginary"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If \\(A = \\begin{pmatrix}1 & 2 \\\\ 3 & 4 \\end{pmatrix} \\) and \\(B = \\begin{pmatrix}5 & 6 \\\\ 7 & 8 \\end{pmatrix}\\), then \\((AB)^{'}\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}19 & 43 \\\\ 22 & 50 \\end{pmatrix} \\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}1 & 0 \\\\ 0 & 1 \\end{pmatrix} \\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}19 & 43 \\\\ 22 & 50 \\end{pmatrix} \\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}19 & 22 \\\\ 43 & 50 \\end{pmatrix} \\)",
            "\\(\\begin{pmatrix}22 & 50 \\\\ 43 & 19 \\end{pmatrix} \\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The two lines of the system \\(6x-4y=10\\), \\(3x-2y=5\\) are",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "parallel",
        "choices": [
            "parallel",
            "intersecting",
            "coincident",
            "independent"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "If the A.M. and G.M. between two given numbers are 81 and 18, respectively, then H.M. is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "99",
            "49.5",
            "4.5",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The most general value of \\(\\theta\\) satisfying the equation \\(3\\tan^{2}\\theta = 1\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(n \\pi \\pm \\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(n \\pi + \\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)",
            "\\(n \\pi \\pm \\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)",
            "\\(2n \\pi \\pm \\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)",
            "\\((-1)^{3}\\alpha + \\frac{\\pi}{6}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "\\(\\tan^{-1}x + \\tan^{-1}\\left(\\frac{1}{x}\\right)\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Depends on \\(x\\)",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{\\pi}{4}\\)",
            "Depends on \\(x\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "In a \\(\\Delta ABC, \\space r\\) is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\((S-a)\\tan \\frac{A}{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\((S-a)\\tan \\frac{A}{2}\\)",
            "\\((S-b) tan \\frac{A}{2}\\)",
            "\\((S-c) \\tan \\frac{A}{2}\\)",
            "\\((S-a) \\tan \\frac{B}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The distance between the two lines \\(3x+4y=6\\) and \\(6x + 8y=15\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{3}{10} \\space units\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{2}{3} \\space units\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{2}{5} \\space units\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{10}{3} \\space units\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{3}{10} \\space units\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "For what value of \\(\\lambda\\) does the equation \\(12x^{2}-10xy+2y^{2}+11x-5y+\\lambda = 0\\) represents a line pair?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "4",
        "choices": [
            "1",
            "2",
            "3",
            "4"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Equation of the circle having ends of its diameter at \\(\\left( -1, \\space 1 \right)\\) and \\(\\left( 0,2 \\right)\\)",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(x^{2}+y^{2}-x-y-2=0\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(x^{2}+y^{2}-x-y-2=0\\)",
            "\\(x^{2}+y^{2}+x+y-2=0\\)",
            "\\(x^{2}+y^{2}-x-2y+2=0\\)",
            "\\(x^{2}+y^{2}-x+2y-2=0\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "The direction cosines of a line equally inclined to the axes are",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}, \\frac{1}{2}, \\frac{1}{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{3}, \\frac{1}{3}, \\frac{1}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\pm \\frac{1}{2}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{2}}\\)",
            "\\(\\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}, \\pm \\frac{1}{\\sqrt{3}}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "Which of the following pair have same dimension?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(LR \\space and \\space CR\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{L}{R} \\space and \\space CR\\)",
            "\\(LR \\space and \\space CR\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{R}{L} \\space and \\space \\left[ LC \\right]^{\\frac{1}{2}}\\)",
            "\\(CR \\space and \\space \\frac{1}{LC}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Math",
        "question": "A bullet fired into a fixed target loses half of its velocity after penetrating 3 cm, the further distance travelled before coming to the rest is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "1 cm",
        "choices": [
            "4 cm",
            "2 cm",
            "3 cm",
            "1 cm"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The horizontal range is \\(4\\sqrt{3}\\) times the maximum height in a projectile motion. The angle of projection is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(45^{\\circ}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(15^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(45^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(30^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(60^{\\circ}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The 'net force acting on a body is zero' then the wrong statement is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Acceleration should be zero",
        "choices": [
            "Body is at rest",
            "Acceleration is not zero",
            "Body is in motion",
            "Acceleration should be zero"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "If length of wire is doubled keeping the diameter constant, it's Young's modulus will",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "remain same",
        "choices": [
            "increases",
            "decreases",
            "remain same",
            "depend upon nature of matter"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The work done to blow a soap bubble of radius 'R' is W, then work done to increase the radius from R to 3R is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "8 W",
        "choices": [
            "2 W",
            "8 W",
            "4 W",
            "9 W"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A metallic ball is immersed in alcohol. The coefficient of cubical expansion of metal is less than that of alcohol. When the system is heated weight of ball is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "choices": [
            "increases",
            "remains unchanged",
            "decreases",
            "first increases and then decreases"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "Latent heat of a substance is zero at",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "critical temperature",
        "choices": [
            "boiling point",
            "critical temperature",
            "melting point",
            "freezing point"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The average Kinetic Energy per degree of freedom per molecule of an ideal gas is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{1}{2}KT\\)",
        "choices": [
            "KT",
            "2KT",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{2}KT\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{3}{4}KT\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "Two spheres of same material have radii in the ration \\(3:2\\). The heat radiated by them at the same temperature will be",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(9:4\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(1:1\\)",
            "\\(4:9\\)",
            "\\(9:4\\)",
            "\\(3:2\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "Light of wavelength 550 nm falls normally on a slit of width \\(22 \\times 10^{-7}m\\), the angular position of second minima from central maxima will be",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(14.5^{\\circ}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(14.5^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(30^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(42^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(62^{\\circ}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A person is in a room whose ceiling and two adjacent walls are mirrors. Number of images formed of an object is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "7",
        "choices": [
            "5",
            "7",
            "6",
            "8"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The refractive index is 1.414 and refracting angle is \\(60^{\\circ}\\), then minimum deviation of light will be",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(60^{\\circ}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(60^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(30^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(45^{\\circ}\\)",
            "\\(72^{\\circ}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A sound wave has frequency 500 Hz and velocity 360 m/s. What is the distance between 2 particles having phase difference \\(60^{\\circ}\\)?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "12 cm",
        "choices": [
            "0.7 cm",
            "70 cm",
            "1.2 cm",
            "12 cm"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "Two fixed charges \\(q\\) and \\(4q\\) are at \\(r\\) distance apart. What will be position of third charge to be placed so that the system will be in equilibrium ?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{r}{2} \\space from \\space 4q\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{2r}{3} \\space from \\space 4q\\)",
            "\\(2r \\space from \\space q\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{r}{2} \\space from \\space q\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{r}{2} \\space from \\space 4q\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "n-equal capacitors are first connected in series and then in parallel. The ratio of maximum to minimum capacitance is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(n^{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(n^{2}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{n^{2}}\\)",
            "\\(n\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{1}{n}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A heater coil is cut into two equal parts and only one part is used in the heater. How will the heat generated vary?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "halved",
        "choices": [
            "one-fourth",
            "doubled",
            "halved",
            "four times"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A 50 V battery is connected across 10 \\Omega resistor. The current in the circuit is 4.5 A. The internal resistance of the battery should be",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(1.1 \\Omega\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(0 \\Omega\\)",
            "\\(5 \\Omega\\)",
            "\\(0.5 \\Omega\\)",
            "\\(1.1 \\Omega\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A magnetic needle kept in a non-uniform magnetic field. It experiences",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "a force and a torque",
        "choices": [
            "a torque but not a force",
            "a force and a torque",
            "neither a force nor a torque",
            "a force but not a torque"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "In LCR circuit, the inductive reactance at resonance frequency is 100 Hz and resistance is \\(5 \\Omega\\), the quality factor of the circuit is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "20",
        "choices": [
            "5000",
            "500",
            "20",
            "95"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "A circuit contains a capacitor of 420 Pf and an inductance L. The value of 'L' to broadcast on Radio at 1020 kHz is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(2.8 \\times 10^{-5} H\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(2.8 \\times 10^{-5} H\\)",
            "\\(7.6 \\times 10^{-5} H\\)",
            "\\(5.8 \\times 10^{-5} H\\)",
            "\\(9.6 \\times 10^{-6} H\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "Electron accelerated from rest to a potential difference of 100 V, its final velocity will be",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(6 \\times 10^{6} m/s\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(5 \\times 10^{5} m/s\\)",
            "\\(3 \\times 10^{6} m/s\\)",
            "\\(4 \\times 10^{5} m/s\\)",
            "\\(6 \\times 10^{6} m/s\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "When a proton collides with an electron, which of the following characteristics of proton increases?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Impulse",
        "choices": [
            "Energy",
            "Wavelength",
            "Frequency",
            "Impulse"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The half life of a radioactive sample is 10 years. Its mean life is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "14.43 years",
        "choices": [
            "12.43 years",
            "16.43 years",
            "14.43 years",
            "Same as half life"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "NPN transistors are most preferred than that of PNP transistor. It is because of",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "None of the above",
        "choices": [
            "Low cost",
            "Capable of handling low power",
            "Low dissipation of energy",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Azimuthal quantum number describes",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "orbital shape",
        "choices": [
            "orbital size",
            "orbital orientation",
            "orbital shape",
            "nuclear stability"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The radioactive rays having highest penetrating power is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\Upsilon \\space rays\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\alpha \\space rays\\)",
            "\\(\\beta \\space rays\\)",
            "\\(\\Upsilon \\space rays\\)",
            "all have equal penetrating power"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Which of the following has an electrovalent linkage?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(MgCl_{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(MgCl_{2}\\)",
            "\\(CH_{4}\\)",
            "\\(SiCl_{4}\\)",
            "\\(CCl_{4}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The element having highest value of electronegativity is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Fluorine",
        "choices": [
            "Chlorine",
            "Fluorine",
            "Bromine",
            "Iodine"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Oxidation number of chromium in \\(Cr_{2}O_{7}\\space^{2-}\\) is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "+6",
        "choices": [
            "+6",
            "+5",
            "+4",
            "+3"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Which of the following is an amphoteric oxide?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(CuO\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(CaO\\)",
            "\\(MgO\\)",
            "\\(CuO\\)",
            "\\(ZnO\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The structure of Buckminister fullerene contains",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "12 six member rings and 20 five member rings",
        "choices": [
            "20 six member rings and 12 five member rings",
            "12 six member rings and 20 five member rings",
            "12 six member rings and 10 five member rings",
            "12 six member rings and 8 five member rings"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Down's process is used for the extraction of",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "sodium",
        "choices": [
            "ammonia",
            "nitric acid",
            "sodium",
            "sulphuric acid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The IUPAC name of iso-butane is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "2-methylpropane",
        "choices": [
            "2-methylpropane",
            "2,2-dimethylpropane",
            "2-methylpropene",
            "2-methylbutane"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "An alkaline \\(KMnO_{4}\\) solution is known as",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Baeyer's reagent",
        "choices": [
            "Tollen's reagent",
            "Baeyer's reagent",
            "Fehling's reagent",
            "Grignard reagent"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "When haloalkane solution is treated with metallic sodium in presence of dry ether, respective alkane is obtained. This reaction is known as",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Wurtz reaction",
        "choices": [
            "Wurtz reaction",
            "Wolf-Kishner reduction",
            "Cannizzaro's reaction",
            "Reimer-Tiemann reaction"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The general formula of alkanes is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(C_{n}H_{2n+2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(C_{n}H_{2n}\\)",
            "\\(C_{n}H_{2n+2}\\)",
            "\\(C_{n}H_{2n-2}\\)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Detection of nitrogen, sulphur and halogens in organic compounds is done by",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Lassaigne's test",
        "choices": [
            "Lassaigne's test",
            "Lucas test",
            "Victor meyer test",
            "Carbylamine test"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The structure of methane is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "tetrahedral",
        "choices": [
            "trigonal planar",
            "linear",
            "tetrahedral",
            "square planar"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Equivalent weight of potassium dichromate in an acidic medium is equal to its",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(\\frac{mol. wt.}{6}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{mol. wt.}{6}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{mol. wt.}{3}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{mol. wt.}{4}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{mol. wt.}{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "An example of Lewis base is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(NH_{3}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(BF_{3}\\)",
            "\\(AlCl_{3}\\)",
            "\\(FeCl_{3}\\)",
            "\\(NH_{3}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "A device which can generate electricity by means of a redox reaction is called",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "choices": [
            "Electrochemical Cell",
            "Galvanic Cell",
            "Voltaic Cell",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "1 calorie is equal to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "4.184 joules",
        "choices": [
            "4.184 joules",
            "5.184 joules",
            "3.184 joules",
            "2.184 joules"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The rate of a reaction depends on",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "choices": [
            "Concentration of reacting species",
            "Temperature",
            "Surface area of the reactants",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Each carbon atom of benzene is",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(sp^{2} \\space hydridized\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(sp^{3} \\space hybridized\\)",
            "\\(sp^{2} \\space hydridized\\)",
            "\\(sp \\space hybridized\\)",
            "\\(sp^{3}d \\space hydridized\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Which is correct for the reaction of Lucas reagent with tertiary alcohol ?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "turbidity appears immediately",
        "choices": [
            "no turbidity occurs at room temperature",
            "turbidity appears within five minutes",
            "turbidity appears immediately",
            "turbidity appears within ten minutes"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Fat is a",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "lipid",
        "choices": [
            "lipid",
            "carbohydrate",
            "protein",
            "amino acid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Bakelite is made by the action of",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "phenol on formaldehyde",
        "choices": [
            "phenol on formaldehyde",
            "urea on formaldehyde",
            "melamine on formaldehyde",
            "ethylene glycol on phthalic acid"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Which of the following compound in called corrosive sublimate?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(HgCl_{2}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(Hg_{2}Cl_{2}\\)",
            "\\(HgCl_{2}\\)",
            "\\(K_{2}[HgI_{4}]\\)",
            "\\(HgI_{2}\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Haematite is an ore of",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Iron",
        "choices": [
            "Iron",
            "Copper",
            "Mercury",
            "Silver"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "The word \"permissible\" is accented on its .......... syllable.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(2^{nd}\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(1^{st}\\)",
            "\\(2^{nd}\\)",
            "\\(3^{rd}\\)",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Which of the following word gets stress on the first syllable?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "Perish",
        "choices": [
            "Perish",
            "Incredible",
            "Incur",
            "Temerity"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "I shall be glad .......... your help in my business.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "of",
        "choices": [
            "in",
            "by",
            "of",
            "with"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "An addicted person is the slave .......... to his drug habit.",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "to",
        "choices": [
            "to",
            "for",
            "on",
            "by"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Give an appropriate synonym to the word \"vendetta\".",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "feud",
        "choices": [
            "pleasant",
            "secret",
            "promise",
            "feud"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Give us appropriate synonym to the word \"acerbity\".",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "acrimony",
        "choices": [
            "mildness",
            "acrimony",
            "unsuitable",
            "extravagant"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Chemistry",
        "question": "Give opposite meaning word to \"replete\".",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "empty",
        "choices": [
            "empty",
            "alarm",
            "full",
            "stuff"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Give opposite meaning word to \"quell\".",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "encourage",
        "choices": [
            "encourage",
            "stop",
            "crush",
            "promote"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "A disease that can be spread by touch is ..........",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "contagious",
        "choices": [
            "pandemic",
            "infectious",
            "endemic",
            "contagious"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Pick the odd word out",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "venison",
        "choices": [
            "lamb",
            "pork",
            "mutton",
            "venison"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "What is the right meaning of the Latin word \"ad nauseam\"?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "to a disgusting degree",
        "choices": [
            "to a disgusting degree",
            "regularly",
            "on duty",
            "rarely"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "I think she will succeed, ..........?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "won't she?",
        "choices": [
            "shan't she?",
            "won't she?",
            "would she?",
            "doesn't she?"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "English",
        "question": "Which of the following is the adjective?",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "autumnal",
        "choices": [
            "width",
            "autumnal",
            "advantage",
            "arrogant"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "On heating a liquid, the refractive index generally",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "decreases",
        "choices": [
            "does not change",
            "decreases",
            "increases",
            "May increase or decrease depending on the rate of heating"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    },
    {
        "subject": "Physics",
        "question": "The torque on an electric dipole of moment \\(\\overrightarrow{p}\\) when placed in an electric field \\(\\overrightarrow{E}\\) is proportional to",
        "programme": "BScsIT",
        "answer": "\\(PE \\sin \\theta\\)",
        "choices": [
            "\\(\\frac{P}{E}\\)",
            "\\(\\frac{E}{P}\\)",
            "\\(P.E\\)",
            "\\(PE \\sin \\theta\\)"
        ],
        "TotalQuestionsToSelect": 25
    }
]
